<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--========================================================================
 "iFolder Help"

 Copyright © 2005 Novell, Inc. All rights reserved. No part of this publication
 may be reproduced, photocopied, stored on a retrieval system, or transmitted
 without the express written consent of the publisher.

 Novell, Inc.
 404 Wyman Street, Suite 500
 Waltham, MA 02451
 U.S.A.
 www.novell.com


 BASELINE PAGE COUNT (based on 200 words per page): 63


 WORD COUNT

       Count    Doctype    Title
      ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
         762    bookinfo   iFolder Help
         251    preface    iFolder Help
        1313    chapter    Overview of iFolder
        4813    chapter    Managing iFolder Accounts and Preferences
        5660    chapter    Managing iFolders
      ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
       12799    book       iFolder Help


 GRAPHICS REFERENCED IN BOOK

       Count       Filename
      ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
           2       ifolder-sync22.png
           2       if_notify_a.png
           2       if_acctasst1_a.png
           2       ifolder-waiting22.png
           2       ifolder24.png
           6       ifolder32.png
           8       ifolder-error_16.png
           2       if_apbrmenu_a.png
          38       ifolder22.png
           2       ifolder-error22.png
           2       prefs-notification32.png
           2       if3_ifcr_share-accessro_a.png
           2       if_preferences_a.png
           2       ifolder-user-current16.png
           4       ifolder-download22.png
           2       ifolder-upload22.png
           2       ifolder-warning22.png
           6       folder_16.gif
           2       if3_sharing_a.png
           2       if_prefaccts_a.png
           4       if_menu_a.png
           2       ifolder-user-owner16.png
           2       if_acctasst2_a.png


 CROSS-REFERENCES

       Count       Type
      ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
          67       xref
           0       link
           0       ulink-xrefext
           0       ulink-xrefexttext
           3       ulink


 URLS REFERENCED IN ULINKS

       URL
      ~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
       http://www.novell.com/documentation/ifolderos/
       http://www.unicode.org
       http://www.novell.com/documentation/ifolder3

========================================================================-->
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//Novell//DTD NovDoc XML V1.0//EN" "novdocx.dtd">



<book revision = "04/26/06" conformance = "ifolder3,doc,yes,4,80"
    lang = "en" id = "user">
<bookinfo id = "bookinfo"><title>iFolder Help</title>
<productname>iFolder&trade;</productname>
<productnumber>3.4</productnumber>
<date>June 30, 2006</date>
<titleabbrev>Help</titleabbrev>
<legalnotice id = "b423epo"><title>Legal Notices</title>
<para>Novell, Inc., makes no representations or warranties with
respect to the contents or use of this documentation, and specifically
disclaims any express or implied warranties of merchantability or
fitness for any particular purpose. Further, Novell, Inc., reserves
the right to revise this publication and to make changes to its
content, at any time, without obligation to notify any person or
entity of such revisions or changes.</para>
<para>Further, Novell, Inc., makes no representations or warranties
with respect to any software, and specifically disclaims any express
or implied warranties of merchantability or fitness for any particular
purpose. Further, Novell, Inc., reserves the right to make changes
to any and all parts of Novell software, at any time, without any
obligation to notify any person or entity of such changes.</para>
<para>Any products or technical information provided under this
Agreement may be subject to U.S. export controls and the trade laws
of other countries. You agree to comply with all export control
regulations and to obtain any required licenses or classification
to export, re-export or import deliverables. You agree not to export
or re-export to entities on the current U.S. export exclusion lists
or to any embargoed or terrorist countries as specified in the U.S.
export laws. You agree to not use deliverables for prohibited nuclear,
missile, or chemical biological weaponry end uses. Please refer
to www.novell.com&sol;info&sol;exports&sol; for more
information on exporting Novell software. Novell assumes no responsibility
for your failure to obtain any necessary export approvals.</para>
<para>Copyright © 2004-2006 Novell, Inc. All rights reserved. Permission
is granted to copy, distribute, and&sol;or modify this document
under the terms of the GNU Free Documentation License (GFDL), Version
1.2 or any later version, published by the Free Software Foundation
with no Invariant Sections, no Front-Cover Texts, and no Back-Cover
Texts. A copy of the GFDL can be found at http:&sol;&sol;www.fsf.org&sol;licenses&sol;fdl.html.</para>
<para>THIS DOCUMENT AND MODIFIED VERSIONS OF THIS DOCUMENT ARE PROVIDED
UNDER THE TERMS OF THE GNU FREE DOCUMENTATION LICENSE WITH THE FURTHER
UNDERSTANDING THAT:</para>
<para>1. THE DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS, WITHOUT WARRANTY
OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESSED OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, WITHOUT LIMITATION,
WARRANTIES THAT THE DOCUMENT OR MODIFIED VERSION OF THE DOCUMENT
IS FREE OF DEFECTS, MERCHANTABLE, FIT FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE,
OR NON-INFRINGING. THE ENTIRE RISK AS TO THE QUALITY, ACCURACY,
AND PERFORMANCE OF THE DOCUMENT OR MODIFIED VERSION OF THE DOCUMENT IS
WITH YOU. SHOULD ANY DOCUMENT OR MODIFIED VERSION PROVE DEFECTIVE
IN ANY RESPECT, YOU (NOT THE INITIAL WRITER, AUTHOR OR ANY CONTRIBUTOR)
ASSUME THE COST OF ANY NECESSARY SERVICING, REPAIR OR CORRECTION.
THIS DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTY CONSTITUTES AN ESSENTIAL PART OF THIS
LICENSE. NO USE OF ANY DOCUMENT OR MODIFIED VERSION OF THE DOCUMENT
IS AUTHORIZED HEREUNDER EXCEPT UNDER THIS DISCLAIMER; AND</para>
<para>2. UNDER NO CIRCUMSTANCES AND UNDER NO LEGAL THEORY, WHETHER
IN TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE), CONTRACT, OR OTHERWISE, SHALL THE
AUTHOR, INITIAL WRITER, ANY CONTRIBUTOR, OR ANY DISTRIBUTOR OF THE
DOCUMENT OR MODIFIED VERSION OF THE DOCUMENT, OR ANY SUPPLIER OF
ANY OF SUCH PARTIES, BE LIABLE TO ANY PERSON FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT,
SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OF ANY CHARACTER INCLUDING,
WITHOUT LIMITATION, DAMAGES FOR LOSS OF GOODWILL, WORK STOPPAGE, COMPUTER
FAILURE OR MALFUNCTION, OR ANY AND ALL OTHER DAMAGES OR LOSSES ARISING OUT
OF OR RELATING TO USE OF THE DOCUMENT AND MODIFIED VERSIONS OF THE
DOCUMENT, EVEN IF SUCH PARTY SHALL HAVE BEEN INFORMED OF THE POSSIBILITY
OF SUCH DAMAGES.</para>
<para>Novell, Inc., has intellectual property rights relating to
technology embodied in the product that is described in this document.
In particular, and without limitation, these intellectual property
rights may include one or more of the U.S. patents listed at http:&sol;&sol;www.novell.com&sol;company&sol;legal&sol;patents&sol; and
one or more additional patents or pending patent applications in
the U.S. and in other countries.</para>
<simplelist><member>Novell, Inc.</member>
<member>404 Wyman Street, Suite 500</member>
<member>Waltham, MA 02451</member>
<member>U.S.A.</member>
<member>www.novell.com</member></simplelist>
<simplelist><member><emphasis>Online Documentation:</emphasis> To
access the online documentation for this and other Novell products,
and to get updates, see www.novell.com&sol;documentation.</member></simplelist></legalnotice>
<legalnotice id = "b423epp"><title>Novell Trademarks</title>
<simplelist><member>GroupWise is a registered trademark of Novell,
Inc., in the United States and other countries.</member>
<member>iFolder is a trademark of Novell, Inc.</member>
<member>Mono is a registered trademark of Novell, Inc., in the United
States and other countries.</member>
<member>Novell is a registered trademark of Novell, Inc., in the
United States and other countries.</member>
<member>Novell iFolder is a registered trademark of Novell, Inc.,
in the United States and other countries.</member>
<member>SUSE is a registered trademark of Novell, Inc., in the United
States and other countries.</member></simplelist></legalnotice>
<legalnotice id = "b423epq"><title>Third-Party Materials</title>
<simplelist><member>All third-party trademarks are the property
of their respective owners.</member></simplelist></legalnotice></bookinfo>

<preface id = "preface" xml:base = "00_preface.xml"><title>iFolder
Help</title>
<para>iFolder&trade; is an open source, file-sharing application
for Linux&ast;, Windows&ast;, and Macintosh&ast; clients. With
iFolder, your local files automatically follow you everywhere---online,
offline, all the time---across computers. You can share files in
multiple iFolders, each with a different group of users. You control
who can participate in an iFolder and their access rights to the
files in it. You can also participate in iFolders that others share
with you.</para>
<para>This help system describes how to use and manage the iFolder
client. </para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para><xref linkend = "overview"
    xrefstyle = "ChapTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "accountsprefs"
    xrefstyle = "ChapTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "myifolders"
    xrefstyle = "ChapTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem></itemizedlist>
<bridgehead id = "b2qz8eu">Audience</bridgehead>
<para>This guide is intended for users of the iFolder client.</para>
<bridgehead id = "additionaldoc">Additional Documentation</bridgehead>
<para>If you are using the iFolder 3.4 or later client with a Novell
iFolder 3.<replaceable>x</replaceable> enterprise server or Web access
server, see the <citetitle>iFolder 3.4 User Guide for Novell iFolder
3.x</citetitle> at the <ulink
    url = "http://www.novell.com/documentation/ifolder3">Novell
iFolder 3.x Documentation Web site</ulink>.</para>
<para>If you are using the iFolder client with an open source server,
see the <citetitle>iFolder User Guide</citetitle> at the <ulink
    url = "http://www.novell.com/documentation/ifolderos/">iFolder
Open Source Documentation Web site</ulink>.</para>
<bridgehead id = "docconventions">Documentation Conventions</bridgehead>
<para>In Novell documentation, a greater-than symbol (>) is used
to separate actions within a step and items in a cross-reference
path.</para>
<para>A trademark symbol (&reg;, &trade;, etc.) denotes
a Novell trademark. An asterisk (&ast;) denotes a third-party trademark.</para>
<para>When a single pathname can be written with a backslash for
some platforms or a forward slash for other platforms, the pathname
is presented with a backslash. Users of platforms that require a forward
slash, such as Linux or UNIX, should use forward slashes as required
by your software.</para></preface>

<chapter conformance = ",doc,yes,4," lang = "en" id = "overview"
    xml:base = "01_overview.xml"><title>Overview of iFolder</title>
<para>iFolder&trade; is a file-sharing application for Linux,
Windows, and Macintosh clients. You can share files in multiple
iFolders, each with a different group of users. You control who
can participate in an iFolder and the access level for each member.
You can also participate in iFolders that others share with you. </para>
<para>This section familiarizes you with the various benefits and
features of iFolder:</para>
<itemizedlist role="subtoc"><listitem><para><xref linkend = "ovwsharing"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "ovwbenefits"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "ovwfeatures"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "ovwxplat" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "ovwnext" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem></itemizedlist>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "ovwsharing"><title>iFolder Sharing</title>
<para>Typically, when you work in multiple locations or in collaboration
with others, you must conscientiously manage file versions. With
iFolder, the most recent version of your files can follow you to
any computer where you have installed the iFolder client and created
an iFolder for them. iFolder also allows you to share multiple iFolders
and their separate content with other authorized users. You decide
who participates in each iFolder and the level of access for each
member. Similarly, you can participate in shared iFolders that are
owned by others in your collaboration environment.</para>
<para>The iFolder client supports sharing by synchronizing files
across multiple computers through a central computer. It allows
you to do the following:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>Share files across computers</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Share files with others</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Own multiple iFolders</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Participate in multiple iFolders that other users
share with you</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Participate as the owner or a member of iFolders
in multiple accounts</para></listitem></itemizedlist></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "ovwbenefits"><title>Benefits of iFolder</title>
<para>iFolder provides the following benefits:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>Integrates with your native desktop
environment, making it easy to create and manage multiple iFolders</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Is highly scalable and flexible, with no practical
limit on the number of iFolders per user or on the number of members
per iFolder</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Allows you to easily and selectively share personal
and business files</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Allows you to control the access level of member
users of the iFolders you own, or where you have the necessary rights
to control the access rights of members</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Transparently updates your files to member iFolders
on multiple workstations</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>When iFolder is running, tracks and logs changes
made while you work offline, and synchronizes those changes when
you connect to the server</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Provides secure authentication of members who access
an iFolder to synchronize its data</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Offers an alternative to exchanging files via e-mail,
which avoids the file-size limits on e-mail attachments and reduces
your e-mail storage requirements</para></listitem></itemizedlist></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "ovwfeatures"><title>Key Features of
iFolder</title>
<para>Before you begin to use iFolder, it is important to understand
the following key features:</para>
<itemizedlist role="subtoc"><listitem><para><xref linkend = "bq1r111"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "bx3bipv" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "bq1r112" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "bq1r113" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "bq1r118" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "bq63xvh" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem></itemizedlist>
<sect2 id = "bq1r111"><title>The iFolder Client </title>
<para>The iFolder client integrates with your operating system to
provide iFolder services in your native desktop environment. iFolder
supports the following operating systems:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>Novell&reg; Linux Desktop 9</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>SUSE&reg; Linux Enterprise Desktop 10 (for
iFolder 3.4 and later)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Windows 2000&sol;XP&sol;2003</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Macintosh OS X v10.3 or later</para></listitem></itemizedlist>
<para>The iFolder client allows you to manage your own iFolders
and to select which shared iFolders to set up on each computer.
For information, see <xref linkend = "myifolders"
    xrefstyle = "HeadingOnPage"/>.</para></sect2>
<sect2 id = "bx3bipv"><title>iFolder Account</title>
<para>You must configure at least one iFolder account before you
can create iFolders. An iFolder account is created when an iFolder
services administrator provisions you as an iFolder user for an
iFolder server. The administrator provides you with a username and
password. For an enterprise, this might be your username or e-mail
address and the related password.</para>
<para>An iFolder session begins when you log in to an iFolder services
account and ends when you log out, or when you exit the iFolder
client. Your iFolders synchronize files with other active iFolders only
when your session is active and you are working online. You can
access data in your local iFolders at any time, whether you are
logged in to the account, or not. For information, see <xref
    linkend = "accounts" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/>.</para></sect2>
<sect2 id = "bq1r112"><title>Shared iFolders</title>
<para>An iFolder is a local directory that selectively shares and
synchronizes files via a central computer with a user-specified
group of users. The iFolder files are accessible to all iFolder
members and can be changed by those with the rights to do so. You
can access your iFolders across multiple workstations and share
them with others.</para>
<para>You work with iFolders directly in your file manager or in
the iFolder browser that is part of the client. Within the iFolder,
you can set up any subdirectory structure that suits your personal
or corporate work habits. The subdirectory structure is constant
across all member iFolders. When you share an iFolder, member users
with the Write right can modify the directory structure, and those changes
apply to all copies of the iFolder. Each user can locate the shared
iFolder anywhere on his or her own computer that satisfies the <xref
    linkend = "locguide" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/>.</para></sect2>
<sect2 id = "bq1r113"><title>iFolder Access Rights</title>
<para>The iFolder client supports the owner and three levels of
access for members of an iFolder: </para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><formalpara id = "bq8voz4"><title>Owner: </title>
<para>Only one user serves as the owner of an iFolder. This is typically
the user who creates the iFolder. The owner user can use the iFolder
client to transfer ownership to another member of the iFolder. </para></formalpara>
<para>The owner of an iFolder has the Full Control right. This user
has read&sol;write access to the iFolder, manages membership
and access rights for member users, and can remove the Full Control
right for any member.</para></listitem>
<listitem><formalpara id = "bq8voz5"><title>Full Control: </title>
<para>A member of the shared iFolder, with the Full Control access
right. This member has read&sol;write access to the iFolder
and manages membership and access rights for all users except the
owner. </para></formalpara></listitem>
<listitem><formalpara id = "bq8voz6"><title>Read&sol;Write: </title>
<para>A member of the shared iFolder, with the Read&sol;Write
access right to directories and files in the iFolder.</para></formalpara></listitem>
<listitem><formalpara id = "bq8voz7"><title>Read Only: </title>
<para>A member of the shared iFolder, with the Read Only access
right to directories and files in the iFolder. This member can modify
a file, but the local changes are not synchronized to other members&rsquo; copies
of the iFolder.</para></formalpara></listitem></itemizedlist>
<para>Any iFolder user can own some iFolders and be a member of
other iFolders. As an owner user, you always have the Full Control
right. As a member user, your level of access in each shared iFolder can
differ, depending on the access granted to you by any member with
the Full Control right.</para></sect2>
<sect2 id = "bq1r118"><title>File Synchronization and Data Management</title>
<para>When you set up an iFolder account, you can enable <guimenu>Remember
My Password</guimenu> so that iFolder can synchronize iFolder invitations
and files in the background as you work. </para>
<para>You can configure the iFolder client to run automatically
each time you log in to your computer&rsquo;s desktop environment.
The session runs in the background as you work with files in your
local iFolders, tracking and logging any changes you make. </para>
<para>You can synchronize the files at specified intervals or on
demand.</para></sect2>
<sect2 id = "bq63xvh"><title>Synchronization Log</title>
<para>The synchronization log displays a log of your iFolder background
activity, such as uploading and downloading files for different
iFolders. </para></sect2></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "ovwxplat"><title>Cross-Platform Considerations</title>
<para>The user interfaces for the Linux, Windows, and Macintosh
versions of the iFolder client conform to interface conventions
of their individual platforms. The way you perform common tasks
is parallel in each platform, but you might observe slight differences
in the buttons, the display area, function labels, the location
of the desktop notification area, the start iFolder preference,
and so on as you perform the tasks. Except where procedures differ
explicitly, this guide provides instructions for only one of the
three platforms.</para>
<para>The following table lists some typical differences in the
client interface:</para>
<informaltable frame = "topbot" rowsep = "0"><tgroup cols = "4">
<colspec colnum = "1" colname = "1" colwidth = "1.458in"/>
<colspec colnum = "2" colname = "2" colwidth = "1.458in"/>
<colspec colnum = "3" colname = "3" colwidth = "1.458in"/>
<colspec colnum = "4" colname = "4" colwidth = "1.458in"/>
<thead>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "bwcl04y">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Task</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Linux</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>Windows</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Macintosh</para></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "bwisd3s">
<entry colname = "1"><para>iFolder menu</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para><guimenu>Quit</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para><guimenu>Exit</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para><guimenu>Quit</guimenu></para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "b41mlmt">
<entry colname = "1"><para><menuchoice><guimenu>iFolder Preferences</guimenu>
<guimenu>Accounts</guimenu></menuchoice> dialog</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para><guimenu>Add</guimenu> button</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para><guimenu>New</guimenu> button</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para><guimenu>Plus</guimenu> (<literal>&plus;</literal>)
button</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "bwcl04z">
<entry colname = "1"><para><menuchoice><guimenu>iFolder Preferences</guimenu>
<guimenu>Accounts</guimenu></menuchoice> dialog</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para><guimenu>Remove</guimenu> button</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para><guimenu>Delete</guimenu> button</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para><guimenu>Minus</guimenu> (<literal>-</literal>)
button</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "bwcl050">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Multiple locations</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para><guimenu>Close</guimenu> button</para>
<para>Actions are committed when you perform the action.</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para><guimenu>OK</guimenu>, <guimenu>Cancel</guimenu>,
and <guimenu>Apply</guimenu> buttons</para>
<para>Actions are committed only when you click <guimenu>Apply</guimenu> or <guimenu>OK</guimenu>.</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para><guimenu>Close</guimenu> button</para>
<para>Actions are committed when you perform the action.</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "bwcl4tf">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>iFolder Preferences</guimenu> dialog</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Add iFolder to the desktop&rsquo;s <guimenu>Startup Programs</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>Select (enable) <guimenu>Start iFolder
when logging In to the desktop</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Add iFolder to the desktop&rsquo;s <guimenu>Startup Programs</guimenu></para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "bwish0p">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Notification area</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Notification area</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>Status and Notification area</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Notification area</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "bxejdm9">
<entry colname = "1"><para><menuchoice><guimenu>iFolders</guimenu>
<guimenu>iFolder</guimenu></menuchoice> menu</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para><guimenu>Properties</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para><guimenu>Properties</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para><guimenu>Get Info</guimenu></para></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup></informaltable></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "ovwnext"><title>What&rsquo;s Next</title>
<para>For information about configuring using the iFolder client,
see the following:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para><xref linkend = "accountsprefs"
    xrefstyle = "ChapTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "myifolders"
    xrefstyle = "ChapTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem></itemizedlist></sect1></chapter>

<chapter revision = "03/20/06" conformance = "none,doc,yes,4,80"
    lang = "en" id = "accountsprefs" xml:base = "04a_accounts.xml">
<title>Managing iFolder Accounts and Preferences</title>
<para>This section discusses how to configure your iFolder&trade; accounts
and how to manage preferences for the iFolder 3.4 and later client.</para>
<itemizedlist role="subtoc"><listitem><para><xref
    linkend = "startclient" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "stopclient"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "accounts" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "login" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "logout" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "accountdetails"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "delacct" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "preferences"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "firewall" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "virusscan"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem></itemizedlist>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "startclient"><title>Starting the iFolder
Client</title>
<para>When iFolder is running, the iFolder application icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject
role="description"><phrase>iFolder Application Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject
role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png" width="11.00pt"
format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> appears
in the Notification area of the taskbar. iFolder is integrated in
the desktop environment. The iFolder emblem (green &ldquo;i&rdquo;) <inlinemediaobject><textobject
role="description"><phrase>iFolder Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject
role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder32.png" width="11pt"
format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder32.png"
width="11pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> appears
on iFolders when viewed in a file manager, on the desktop, or in
the iFolder Browser. </para>
<important>
<para>The Notification area of the taskbar must be enabled in order
for the iFolder application icon to be displayed when iFolder is
running. </para></important>
<para>You can work locally with files in your local iFolders at
any time. Whenever the iFolder client is running, it logs the changes
you make to local iFolder data as you work. If you make changes
to local iFolder data when iFolder is not running, iFolder identifies
and logs the differences the next time you start iFolder.</para>
<para>When iFolder is not running, iFolders appears as a normal
folder <inlinemediaobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/folder_16.gif"
width="11.00pt" format="GIF"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/folder_16.gif"
width="11.00pt" format="gif"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> in
the file manager or on the desktop. You can access files in your
local copy of an iFolder, but you cannot manage iFolders. In addition,
you must log in to an account to create an iFolder or synchronize
its files.</para>
<para>For information about stopping the iFolder client, see <xref
    linkend = "stopclient" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/>.</para>
<para></para>
<sect2 id = "b4064a7"><title>Linux</title>
<bridgehead id = "b40miua">Starting iFolder Automatically on Login</bridgehead>
<para>To enable iFolder to start automatically when you log in to
the desktop, do one of the following:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>Open the applications menu, click <guimenu>More
Applications</guimenu>, locate and right-click <guimenu>iFolder
3</guimenu>, then select <guimenu>Add to Startup Programs</guimenu> from
the menu.</para>
<informalfigure pgwide = "0"><mediaobject><textobject role="description"><phrase>iFolder
3 Application Browser Menu</phrase></textobject>
<imageobject role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/if_apbrmenu_a.png"
width="103pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/if_apbrmenu_a.png"
width="103pt" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></informalfigure></listitem>
<listitem><para>Make sure iFolder is running when you log out, then
save the session setup. Select this session option when you log
in to the desktop.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Open a terminal window, log in as the root user,
then run <filename>&sol;opt&sol;gnome&sol;bin&sol;gnome-session-properties</filename> to
add iFolder as a program to start when you log in to your computer.</para></listitem></itemizedlist>
<para>To disable iFolder from starting automatically on login, do
one of the following:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>Open the applications menu, locate
and right-click <guimenu>iFolder 3</guimenu>, then select <guimenu>Remove
from Startup Programs</guimenu>.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Make sure iFolder is not running when you log out,
then save the session setup. Select this session option when you
log in to the desktop.</para></listitem></itemizedlist>
<bridgehead id = "b40mhcz">Starting iFolder on Demand</bridgehead>
<procedure id = "b25pz8o"><step id = "bw187q5"><para>Log in to your
computer with the local Linux user identity you want to use when
you create iFolders.</para></step>
<step id = "bw18fdr"><para>Use one of the following methods to start
iFolder:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>In the taskbar, open the applications
menu, click <guimenu>More Applications</guimenu>, locate <guimenu>iFolder
3</guimenu> by searching or scrolling through the available options,
right-click iFolder 3, then select <guimenu>Start iFolder 3</guimenu>.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Open a terminal shell, then enter</para>
<screen>
&sol;opt&sol;novell&sol;ifolder3&sol;bin&sol;ifolder
</screen></listitem></itemizedlist></step></procedure></sect2>
<sect2 id = "b406cyo"><title>Windows</title>
<bridgehead id = "b40mehp">Starting iFolder Automatically on Login</bridgehead>
<para>When you install the iFolder client, you can configure iFolder
to start automatically on login by selecting <guimenu>Start iFolder
when logging in to the desktop</guimenu> as one of the install options. </para>
<para>To enable iFolder to start automatically when you log in to
the desktop:</para>
<procedure id = "b41mcvf"><step id = "b41mcvg"><para>Right-click
the iFolder application icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject role="description"><phrase>iFolder
Application Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png" width="11.00pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject>,
then select <guimenu>Preferences</guimenu> to open the iFolder Preferences
dialog box to the <guimenu>General</guimenu> tab.</para></step>
<step id = "b41mcvh"><para>Select <guimenu>Start iFolder When Logging
In to the Desktop</guimenu>, then click <guimenu>Apply</guimenu>.</para></step>
<step id = "b41mcvi"><para>Click <guimenu>OK</guimenu> to close
the iFolders Preferences dialog box.</para></step></procedure>
<para>To disable iFolder from starting automatically when you log
in:</para>
<procedure id = "b41m94g"><step id = "b41m94h"><para>Right-click
the iFolder application icon, then select <guimenu>Preferences</guimenu> to
open the iFolder Preferences dialog box to the <guimenu>General</guimenu> tab.</para></step>
<step id = "b41m9ty"><para>Deselect <guimenu>Start iFolder When
Logging In to the Desktop</guimenu>, then click <guimenu>Apply</guimenu>.</para></step>
<step id = "b41mac7"><para>Click <guimenu>OK</guimenu> to close
the iFolders Preferences dialog box.</para></step></procedure>
<bridgehead id = "b40ment">Starting iFolder on Demand</bridgehead>
<procedure id = "b25pz8p"><step id = "bw08fxw"><para>Log on to the
computer with the local Windows user identity you want to use when
you create iFolders.</para></step>
<step id = "bw08fxx"><para>If iFolder does not start automatically
on successful logon, start iFolder by clicking <menuchoice><guimenu>Start</guimenu>
<guimenu>Programs</guimenu><guimenu>iFolder 3</guimenu></menuchoice>,
then select the <guimenu>iFolder 3 Client</guimenu> application. </para></step></procedure></sect2>
<sect2 id = "b406d69"><title>Macintosh</title>
<bridgehead id = "b40mf88">Starting iFolder Automatically on Login</bridgehead>
<para>To enable iFolder to start automatically when you log in to
your Macintosh computer, add iFolder to the <guimenu>Startup Items</guimenu>.</para>
<para>To disable iFolder from starting automatically, remove iFolder
from the <guimenu>Startup Items</guimenu>.</para>
<bridgehead id = "b40mfcg">Starting iFolder on Demand</bridgehead>
<para>To start iFolder on demand:</para>
<procedure id = "b25pz8q"><step id = "bw08fy1"><para>Log in to your
computer with the local Macintosh user identity you want to use
when you create iFolders.</para></step>
<step id = "bw08fy2"><para>Use one of the following methods to start
iFolder: </para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>Open the <guimenu>Applications</guimenu> menu,
select the <guimenu>Internet</guimenu> submenu, then select <guimenu>iFolder</guimenu>. </para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Open a terminal shell, log in as the root user,
then enter </para>
<screen>
&sol;opt&sol;novell&sol;ifolder3&sol;bin&sol;ifolder
</screen></listitem></itemizedlist></step></procedure></sect2></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "stopclient"><title>Stopping the iFolder
Client</title>
<para>To stop the iFolder client:</para>
<procedure id = "b41k315"><step id = "b41k316"><para>Right-click
the iFolder application icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject role="description"><phrase>iFolder
Application Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png" width="11.00pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> in
the Notification area, then select <guimenu>Quit</guimenu>.</para>
<informalfigure pgwide = "0"><mediaobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/if_menu_a.png" width="78.5pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/if_menu_a.png"
width="78.5pt" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></informalfigure></step></procedure>
<para>Files are synchronized with your iFolder server account only
when you are connected to the iFolder server. You can stop synchronization
by logging out of an account. iFolder continues to run in the background.
For information, see <xref linkend = "logout"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/>.</para></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "accounts"><title>Configuring an iFolder
Account</title>
<para>Use the iFolder Account Assistant to add and configure a new
account. You must configure at least one iFolder account before
you can create iFolders or share iFolders on your system. You can
create only one account for any given iFolder host service, but
you can have multiple accounts. You can log in separately to each
account and be logged in concurrently to multiple accounts.</para>
<para>Multiple users with different local login identities can have
iFolders on the same computer. iFolder prompts the active user to
set up an account on the first time the iFolder client runs under
that local user identity.</para>
<para>To configure a new account:</para>
<procedure id = "b25pz8r"><step id = "bviaku6"><para>Access the <guimenu>iFolder
Account Assistant</guimenu>, using one of the following methods:</para>
<informalfigure pgwide = "0"><mediaobject><textobject role="description"><phrase>iFolder
Account Assistant Welcome Page</phrase></textobject>
<imageobject role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/if_acctasst1_a.png"
width="180pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/if_acctasst1_a.png"
width="180pt" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></informalfigure>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>The first time you start iFolder under
your current local login identity, iFolder prompts you to set up
an iFolder account. Click <guimenu>Yes</guimenu> to go directly
to the <guimenu>iFolder Account Assistant</guimenu>.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Right-click the iFolder application icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject
role="description"><phrase>iFolder Application Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject
role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png" width="11.00pt"
format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> in
the Notification area, select <guimenu>Account Settings</guimenu> to
open the iFolder Preferences dialog box to the <guimenu>Accounts</guimenu> tab,
then click <guimenu>Add</guimenu> to open the <guimenu>iFolder Account
Assistant</guimenu>.</para></listitem></itemizedlist></step>
<step id = "bviamdh"><para>Follow the on-screen instructions to
specify the following values:</para>
<informaltable frame = "topbot" rowsep = "0"><tgroup cols = "2">
<colspec colnum = "1" colname = "1" colwidth = "1.108in"/>
<colspec colnum = "2" colname = "2" colwidth = "4.433in"/>
<thead>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "bvibwik">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Parameter</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Description</para></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "bvibwil">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>iFolder Server Address</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>The DNS name or IP address of the iFolder
enterprise server where you have an account. Get this information
from your iFolder administrator.</para>
<para>For example: <literal>svr21.example.com</literal> or <literal>192.168.1.1</literal></para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "bvibwim">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>User Name</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Specify your user identity for this account.
Your iFolder administrator decides whether the format you should
use is your network user ID (LDAP common name) or your e-mail address.</para>
<para>For example, if your name is John Smith with a user ID of <literal>jsmith</literal> and
an e-mail address of <literal>john.smith&commat;example.com</literal>,
your administrator configures a setting for the server that determines
which of the two formats to accept in the <guimenu>Username</guimenu> field
for authentication purposes.</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "bvibwin">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Password</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Specify the password for your username. </para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "bvibwio">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Remember My Password</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Select <guimenu>Remember My Password</guimenu> to
log in automatically to this iFolder account whenever you log in
to your computer. </para>
<para>If your network password changes, automatic authentication
fails gracefully the next time iFolder attempts to log in to the
iFolder account. iFolder prompts you to log in with your new password
and allows you to specify and save the new password.</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "bvibwiq">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Account Is Default</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>When you have multiple accounts, select <guimenu>Account
Is Default </guimenu>to make this account the one selected by default
in the drop-down list of accounts when you create and upload iFolders.</para></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup></informaltable></step>
<step id = "bvib17w"><para>Verify that the information you entered
is correct, return to previous pages to make corrections if necessary,
then click <guimenu>Connect</guimenu> to validate the settings by
logging in to the iFolder server.</para>
<informalfigure pgwide = "0"><mediaobject><textobject role="description"><phrase>iFolder
Account Assistant Verify and Connect Page</phrase></textobject>
<imageobject role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/if_acctasst2_a.png"
width="180pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/if_acctasst2_a.png"
width="180pt" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></informalfigure></step>
<step id = "b2m63qj"><para>If you are prompted to <guimenu>Accept
the certificate of this server</guimenu>, click <guimenu>Details</guimenu> to
review the certificate information, then click <guimenu>Yes</guimenu> to
accept it if it is good. </para>
<para>If you do not accept the certificate, you cannot connect to
the server.</para></step>
<step id = "b407oqi"><para>On successful connection, click <guimenu>Finish</guimenu> to
close the iFolder Account Assistant.</para>
<para>iFolder synchronizes the user list for the specified account
and identifies iFolders that are available for download. This initial
download can take a few seconds to a few minutes, depending on the
size of the user list for the account. </para></step>
<step id = "b2m64i3"><para>Verify that the account you set up appears
in the list of accounts</para>
<substeps id = "b41ned8"><step id = "b41ned9"><para>Right-click
the iFolder application icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject role="description"><phrase>iFolder
Application Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png" width="11.00pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> in
the Notification area, then select <guimenu>Preferences</guimenu> from
the menu to open the <guimenu>iFolder Preferences</guimenu> dialog
box to the <guimenu>Accounts</guimenu> tab. </para>
<para>When you are connected to the iFolder server, the <guimenu>Online</guimenu> check
box is selected.</para>
<informalfigure pgwide = "0"><mediaobject><textobject role="description"><phrase>Accounts
Tab of the iFolder Preferences Dialog Box</phrase></textobject>
<imageobject role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/if_prefaccts_a.png"
width="180pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/if_prefaccts_a.png"
width="180pt" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></informalfigure></step>
<step id = "bvib1d8"><para>Close the iFolder Preferences dialog
box.</para></step></substeps></step>
<step id = "bvwsa5n"><para>Set up iFolders for the account using
either of these methods.</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>Right-click the iFolder application
icon in the Notification area, then select <guimenu>iFolders</guimenu> to open
the iFolder browser. Continue with <xref linkend = "createifolder"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/>.</para>
<informalfigure pgwide = "0"><mediaobject><textobject role="description"><phrase>iFolder
Client Menu</phrase></textobject>
<imageobject role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/if_menu_a.png"
width="78.5pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/if_menu_a.png"
width="78.5pt" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></informalfigure></listitem>
<listitem><para>If iFolders for this account are available for download
from the server, an iFolder Notification message <inlinemediaobject><textobject
role="description"><phrase>Balloon Notification Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject
role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/prefs-notification32.png"
width="11pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/prefs-notification32.png"
width="11pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> pops
up adjacent to the Notification area of the taskbar. Click the message
to open the iFolder browser. Continue with <xref
    linkend = "setupifolder" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/>.</para></listitem></itemizedlist></step></procedure></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "login"><title>Logging In to an iFolder
Account</title>
<para>You can work locally with files in the iFolder directories
at any time. You must be logged in to an iFolder account to synchronize
the user list, synchronize iFolder data, upload new iFolders, download
shared iFolders, share iFolders, and manage iFolders. You can log
in separately and be logged in concurrently to multiple accounts. </para>
<para>Use one of the following login methods for each account:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><formalpara id = "b40gpos"><title>Log In
Automatically:</title>
<para>Enable <guimenu>Remember My Password</guimenu> for your iFolder
account if you want to log in automatically whenever the iFolder
client starts. You can enable Remember My Password when you configure
the account or by modifying the account settings later.</para></formalpara>
<para>Whenever your password changes, automatic authentication fails
gracefully the next time iFolder attempts to log in to the iFolder
account. iFolder prompts you to log in, then you can enter the new
password. Enable <guimenu>Remember My Password</guimenu> again if
desired.</para></listitem>
<listitem><formalpara id = "b40gq44"><title>Log In As Needed:</title>
<para>Disable <guimenu>Remember My Password</guimenu> if you want
to log in to an iFolder account only as needed.</para></formalpara></listitem></itemizedlist>
<para>To enable or disable <guimenu>Remember My Password</guimenu> for
an existing iFolder account:</para>
<procedure id = "b25pz8s"><step id = "bvwrn0v"><para>Right-click
the iFolder application icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject role="description"><phrase>iFolder
Application Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png" width="11.00pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> in
the Notification area, then select <guimenu>Account Settings</guimenu> to
open the iFolder Preferences dialog box to the <guimenu>Accounts</guimenu> tab.</para></step>
<step id = "bvwrn0w"><para>Select the iFolder account, then click <guimenu>Properties</guimenu> to
view its setting in the iFolder Account Assistant.</para></step>
<step id = "bvwrhna"><para>Follow the onscreen instructions to specify
the password.</para></step>
<step id = "bvwrhn9"><para>Select (enable) or deselect (disable) <guimenu>Remember
My Password</guimenu>.</para></step>
<step id = "b41npf3"><para>Verify the settings you entered, and
go back to modify them if necessary. </para></step>
<step id = "b41nqa7"><para>Click <guimenu>Connect</guimenu> to save
your changes and log in to the server.</para></step></procedure>
<para>To log in to an iFolder account:</para>
<procedure id = "b25pz8t"><step id = "bvwntnx"><para>Right-click
the iFolder application icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject role="description"><phrase>iFolder
Application Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png" width="11.00pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> in
the Notification area, then select <guimenu>Account Settings</guimenu>.</para></step>
<step id = "bvwnufo"><para>Select the iFolder account, then select
the <guimenu>Online</guimenu> check box beside it.</para></step>
<step id = "bvwnv0e"><para>If prompted for a password, specify the
password, then click <guimenu>Connect</guimenu>.</para>
<para>If <guimenu>Remember My Password</guimenu> is enabled for
the account, you are not prompted to enter a password unless your
password has expired. </para>
<para>If login fails, an error message reports the cause, such as
password failure. </para></step>
<step id = "bvws3f9"><para>On successful connection, close the <guimenu>iFolders
Properties</guimenu> dialog box.</para></step></procedure></sect1>
<sect1 id = "logout"><title>Logging Out of an iFolder Account</title>
<para>Log out of an iFolder account whenever you want to work offline. </para>
<sect2 id = "b41m00c"><title>Linux or Macintosh</title>
<procedure id = "b41m0dk"><step id = "b41m5bn"><para>Right-click
the iFolder application icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject role="description"><phrase>iFolder
Application Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png" width="11.00pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> in
the Notification area, then select <guimenu>Account Settings</guimenu> to
open the iFolder Preferences dialog to the <guimenu>Accounts</guimenu> tab.</para></step>
<step id = "b41m11x"><para>Locate the account you want to manage,
then deselect the <guimenu>Online</guimenu> check box beside it
to disconnect from the iFolder server.</para></step>
<step id = "b41m3c9"><para>Click <guimenu>Close</guimenu> to close
the iFolders Preferences dialog box.</para></step></procedure></sect2>
<sect2 id = "b41m5bo"><title>Windows</title>
<procedure id = "b41m5bp"><step id = "b41m5bq"><para>Right-click
the iFolder application icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject role="description"><phrase>iFolder
Application Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png" width="11.00pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> in
the Notification area, then select <guimenu>Account Settings</guimenu> to
open the iFolder Preferences dialog to the <guimenu>Accounts</guimenu> tab.</para></step>
<step id = "b41m5br"><para>Locate the account you want to manage,
then deselect the <guimenu>Online</guimenu> check box beside it.</para></step>
<step id = "b41m5bs"><para>Click <guimenu>Apply</guimenu> to disconnect
from the iFolder server, then click <guimenu>OK</guimenu> to close
the iFolders Preferences dialog box.</para></step></procedure></sect2></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "accountdetails"><title>Viewing and
Modifying iFolder Account Settings</title>
<para>The following parameters can be viewed in the Account Settings
and Account Properties dialog boxes, as described below.</para>
<table id = "b41qbpp" frame = "topbot" rowsep = "1" pgwide = "0">
<title>Account Settings and Properties</title><tgroup cols = "4">
<colspec colnum = "1" colname = "1" colwidth = "0.972in"/>
<colspec colnum = "2" colname = "2" colwidth = "2.917in"/>
<colspec colnum = "3" colname = "3" colwidth = "0.972in"/>
<colspec colnum = "4" colname = "4" colwidth = "0.972in"/>
<thead>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b41qens">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Parameter</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Description</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>Location(s)</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Modifiable by User (Yes&sol;No)</para></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b41qent">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Online</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Indicates whether you are currently connected
to the iFolder server for an account.</para>
<para>Select the <guimenu>Online</guimenu> check box beside the
account to connect to the iFolder server for this account.</para>
<para>Deselect the <guimenu>Online</guimenu> check box beside the
account to disconnect from the iFolder server.</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para><menuchoice><guimenu>iFolder Preferences </guimenu>
<guimenu>Accounts</guimenu></menuchoice> tab</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Yes</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b41qenu">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Name</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Displays the descriptive name of the
iFolder server where your iFolders are stored for the account. This name
is supplied by the server and is controlled by the iFolder administrator. </para>
<para>This setting cannot be modified by users.</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para><menuchoice><guimenu>iFolder Preferences </guimenu>
<guimenu>Accounts</guimenu></menuchoice> tab</para>
<para><guimenu>Account Properties</guimenu> > <guimenu>Server</guimenu> tab</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>No</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b41r0iq">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Address</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Displays the DNS name or IP address of
the iFolder enterprise server where you have an account. Get this
information from your iFolder administrator.</para>
<para>For example: <literal>svr21.example.com</literal> or <literal>192.168.1.1</literal></para>
<para>You can modify the address but you must be disconnected from
the iFolder server when you make the change.</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para><guimenu>Account Properties</guimenu> > <guimenu>Server</guimenu> tab</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Yes</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b41r0ir">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Server description</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Displays information about the iFolder
server such as its service location and iFolder administrator contact
information. The description is supplied by the server and is controlled
by the iFolder administrator. </para>
<para>This setting cannot be modified by users.</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para><guimenu>Account Properties</guimenu> > <guimenu>Server</guimenu> tab</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>No</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b41qenv">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>User Name</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Displays the user identity for this account,
such as your network user ID (LDAP common name) or your e-mail address.
This setting cannot be modified. </para>
<para>The username is specified when you set up the account in the
iFolder Account Assistant. It cannot be modified for an existing
account.</para>
<para>To use a different username on the same server, you must delete
the existing account, then create a different account for it.</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para><menuchoice><guimenu>iFolder Preferences </guimenu>
<guimenu>Accounts</guimenu></menuchoice> tab</para>
<para><guimenu>Account Properties</guimenu> > <guimenu>Identity</guimenu> tab</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>No</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b41r0iu">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Password</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Allows you to specify the password for
your username. </para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para><guimenu>Account Properties</guimenu> > <guimenu>Identity</guimenu> tab</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Yes</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b41r6vf">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Remember password</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Indicates whether iFolder automatically
logs in for you whenever iFolder starts. If the account&rsquo;s <guimenu>Automatically
connect</guimenu> parameter is enabled (default), then it attempts
to connect with the saved password.</para>
<para>Select <guimenu>Remember password</guimenu> to log in automatically to
this iFolder account whenever you log in to your computer. </para>
<para>If your network password changes, automatic authentication
fails gracefully the next time iFolder attempts to log in to the
iFolder account. iFolder prompts you to log in with your new password
and allows you to specify and save the new password.</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para><guimenu>Account Properties</guimenu> > <guimenu>Identity</guimenu> tab</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Yes</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b41r6vg">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Quota</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Reports the total amount of space allocated
to your iFolder account on the enterprise server. This value might
be the default quota set for all users, or a user-specific quota.
If no quota is set, the value is empty or <literal>N&sol;A</literal> (Not
Applicable).</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para><guimenu>Account Properties</guimenu> > <guimenu>Disk
Space</guimenu> tab</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>No</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b41r6vh">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Used</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Reports the total amount of space currently
in use by all the iFolders you own for this account. It does not
include space used by iFolders that are shared with you but owned
by others.</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para><guimenu>Account Properties</guimenu> > <guimenu>Disk
Space</guimenu> tab</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>No</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b41r6vi">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Available</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Reports the total amount of space currently available
to you for iFolders on this iFolder account. The value is equal
to the quota minus the used space.</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para><guimenu>Account Properties</guimenu> > <guimenu>Disk
Space</guimenu> tab</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>No</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b41r0is">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Automatically connect</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>If this value is selected (enabled),
iFolder connects to this account automatically when iFolder starts. Deselect
the setting to disable the account from connecting.</para>
<para>This setting governs only client-side ability to enable or
disable the account.</para>
<para>When you use iFolder with a Novell&reg; iFolder&reg; 3.<replaceable>x</replaceable> server,
the iFolder system administrator can disable your iFolder account
(usually temporarily) on the server side. You can expect the following
behavior when this occurs:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>If you are logged in when the account
is disabled from the server side, you can manage your iFolders and
your iFolder data continues to synchronize with the server until you
end your session by logging out or disabling synchronization, or
until the server disconnects your session, whichever occurs first.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>If the account is disabled on the server side, you
receive a pop-up message informing you that the account is disabled
whenever you attempt to log in. Contact your iFolder system administrator
for assistance. </para></listitem></itemizedlist></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para><guimenu>Account Properties</guimenu>,
on all tabs</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Yes</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "b41r0it">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Account is default</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>When you have multiple accounts, select
the check box for <guimenu>Account is default </guimenu>to make
this account the one selected by default in the drop-down list of accounts
when you create and upload iFolders.</para>
<para>This value cannot be modified if you have only a single account.</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para><guimenu>Account Properties</guimenu>,
on all tabs</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Yes, if you have multiple accounts</para></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup></table>
<procedure id = "b3yur40"><step id = "b3yure0"><para>Right-click
the iFolder application icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject role="description"><phrase>iFolder
Application Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png" width="11.00pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> in
the Notification area, then select <guimenu>Account Settings</guimenu> to
open iFolder Preferences to the <guimenu>Accounts</guimenu> tab. </para></step>
<step id = "b41o1cn"><para>In the Accounts report, you can manage
the following parameters for each account:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>Online (select to connect; deselect
to disconnect)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Name (view only)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>User Name (view only)</para></listitem></itemizedlist></step>
<step id = "byku4l9"><para>Select the iFolder account you want to
manage, then click <guimenu>Properties</guimenu> to open the <replaceable>Account</replaceable> Properties
dialog box to the <guimenu>Server</guimenu> tab.</para></step>
<step id = "b41qa9p"><para>On the <guimenu>Server</guimenu> tab,
you can manage the following parameters for the selected account:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>Name (view only)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Address (view only if connected; modifiable if disconnected)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Server description (view only; scroll to view all
information)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Automatically connect (select to enable; deselect
to disable)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Account is default (select to enable; available
only if multiple accounts exist)</para></listitem></itemizedlist></step>
<step id = "b41qa2i"><para>Select the <guimenu>Identity</guimenu> tab
to manage the following parameters for the selected account:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>User Name (view only)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Password (specify the password)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Remember password (select to enable; deselect to
enable</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Automatically connect (select to enable; deselect
to disable)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Account is default (select to enable; available
only if multiple accounts exist)</para></listitem></itemizedlist></step>
<step id = "b41q9tl"><para>Select the <guimenu>Disk Space</guimenu> tab
to manage the following parameters for the selected account:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>Quota (view only)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Used (view only)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Available (view only)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Automatically connect (select to enable; deselect
to disable)</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Account is default (select to enable; available
only if multiple accounts exist)</para></listitem></itemizedlist></step>
<step id = "b41rjds"><para>When you are done, close the <guimenu>Account
Properties</guimenu> dialog box, then close the <guimenu>iFolder Preferences</guimenu> dialog
box.</para></step></procedure></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "delacct"><title>Deleting an iFolder
Account</title>
<para>You can specify whether to remove an account only from the
current computer, or whether to also remove the iFolders you own
from the server. </para>
<para>If you remove an iFolder account only from your computer:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>The local iFolders for this account
are reverted to normal folders. Use a file manager to locate and
delete the local copy of the data if it is not needed.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>You can continue to access the iFolders from other
computers with the iFolder client. </para></listitem>
<listitem><para>When the iFolder client is used with a Novell iFolder
3.<replaceable>x</replaceable> enterprise server, you can also access files
from anywhere with Novell iFolder 3.<replaceable>x</replaceable> Web
access.</para></listitem></itemizedlist>
<para>If you remove your iFolder account from the server: </para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>All of the iFolders you own are unshared.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>The local copies of iFolders on member computers
are reverted to normal folders. Use a file manager to locate and
delete the local copy of the data if it is not needed.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>The iFolder and its contents are removed from the
server.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>You are removed as a member of iFolders that others
shared with you.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>The account is removed from the local computer.</para></listitem></itemizedlist>
<para>If you decide to use this account again on this or another
computer, you must set up the account and its iFolders just as you
did when it was new.</para>
<para>To delete an iFolder account:</para>
<procedure id = "b25pz8v"><step id = "bvwspv2"><para>Right-click
the iFolder application icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject role="description"><phrase>iFolder
Application Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png" width="11.00pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> in
the Notification area, then select <guimenu>Account Settings</guimenu> to
open the iFolder Preferences dialog box to the Accounts tab.</para></step>
<step id = "bvwspv3"><para>Select the iFolder account you want to
delete, then click <guimenu>Delete</guimenu>.</para></step>
<step id = "bvwspqf"><para>A message prompts you to determine the
extent of the delete action. Do one of the following:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><formalpara id = "bvwsuhg"><title>Remove
the iFolder Account from Only the Current Computer:</title>
<para>Make sure to deselect <guimenu>Remove My iFolder and Files
from the Server</guimenu>, then click <guimenu>Yes</guimenu>.</para></formalpara></listitem>
<listitem><formalpara id = "bvwsxkq"><title>Remove the iFolder Account
and Your iFolders and Files from the Server:</title>
<para>Select <guimenu>Remove My iFolder and Files from the Server</guimenu>,
then click <guimenu>Yes</guimenu>.</para></formalpara></listitem>
<listitem><formalpara id = "bvwsxkr"><title>Cancel the Delete: </title>
<para>Click <guimenu>No</guimenu> to back out of the delete action.
Your account and its iFolders remain untouched.</para></formalpara></listitem></itemizedlist></step></procedure></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "preferences"><title>Configuring iFolder
Preferences for the Client</title>
<procedure id = "b25pz8w"><step id = "bvibeb7"><para>Right-click
the iFolder application icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject role="description"><phrase>iFolder
Application Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png" width="11.00pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> in
the Notification area, then select <guimenu>Preferences</guimenu> to
open the iFolder Preferences dialog box to the <guimenu>General</guimenu> tab.</para>
<informalfigure pgwide = "0"><mediaobject><textobject role="description"><phrase>General
Tab of the iFolder Preferences Dialog Box</phrase></textobject>
<imageobject role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/if_preferences_a.png"
width="180 pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/if_preferences_a.png"
width="180 pt" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></informalfigure></step>
<step id = "bvibeba"><para>Specify your preferences the following:</para>
<informaltable frame = "topbot" rowsep = "0"><tgroup cols = "2">
<colspec colnum = "1" colname = "1" colwidth = "1.108in"/>
<colspec colnum = "2" colname = "2" colwidth = "4.433in"/>
<thead>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "btvqywm">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Parameter</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Description</para></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "btvr5uc">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Start iFolder When Logging In to
the Desktop</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Select this option to launch iFolder
whenever you log in with the local username where you set up the
iFolder account. For those accounts where you have enabled <guimenu>Remember
My Password</guimenu>, synchronization occurs in the background
at the specified Synchronization Interval.</para>
<para>Deselect this option to start iFolder manually.</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "btvqywo">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Show Confirmation Dialog When Creating
iFolders</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Select this option to receive a confirmation
message each time you create an iFolder, in addition to the normal
visual cues such as the iFolder appearing in the list of iFolders.</para>
<para>Deselect this option to stop receiving the confirmation message.</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "bvhdvf7">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Notify of Shared iFolders</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Select this option to enable a pop-up
message in the Notification area whenever you receive a new invitation
to share an iFolder. </para>
<para>Invitations are retrieved based on the <guimenu>Synchronization
Interval</guimenu> you specify in iFolder Preferences. The interval
controls the synchronization of files, iFolder share invitations,
and the list of users. You can also click <guimenu>Refresh</guimenu> to
update invitations on demand.</para>
<para>Deselect this option to disable the pop-up message behavior
for invitations.</para>
<para>You can select <guimenu>Show Available iFolders</guimenu> in
the iFolder browser whenever iFolder is running to view a list of
iFolders that are available to download on your current computer.</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "bvhdvf8">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Notify of Conflicts</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Select this option to enable a pop-up
message in the Notification area whenever a conflict occurs when
synchronizing files. </para>
<para>Deselect this option to disable the pop-up message behavior
for synchronization conflicts.</para>
<para>Whenever conflicts occur, the iFolder Error icon <inlinemediaobject><imageobject
role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder-error_16.png" width="11.00pt"
format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder-error_16.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> is
displayed on the iFolder when iFolder is running.</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "bviaxn9">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Notify When a User Joins</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Select this option to enable a pop-up
message in the Notification area whenever a user accepts an invitation
to share an iFolder. Acceptance is keyed to when the user actually
sets up the iFolder on his or her own computer. </para>
<para>Deselect this option to disable the pop-up message behavior
for user share confirmation.</para>
<para>You can view a complete list of iFolder users whenever iFolder
is running by selecting the iFolder, then clicking <guimenu>Share
with</guimenu> to open the iFolder Properties dialog box to the
Sharing tab.</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "bviaxna">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Synchronization</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><formalpara id = "byktvwf"><title>Automatically
Synchronize iFolders: </title>
<para>Select this check box to enable synchronization for all iFolders
on this computer under your current local login&sol;logon identity.
Deselect the check box to disable synchronization.</para></formalpara>
<formalpara id = "byktwky"><title>Synchronize iFolders Every: </title>
<para>Specify the minimum interval to use for synchronizing iFolders
on this computer under your current local login&sol;logon identity.
Specify the value and units.</para></formalpara>
<para>If you use the iFolder client with Novell iFolder 3.<replaceable>x</replaceable>,
the effective minimum synchronization interval is always the largest
value of the following settings:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>The system policy (default of zero
(<literal>0</literal>), unless there is a user policy set. If a
user policy is set, the user policy overrides the system policy,
whether the user policy is larger or smaller in value.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>The local machine policy, or the setting on the
client machine synchronizing with the server.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>The iFolder (collection) policy.</para></listitem></itemizedlist></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup></informaltable></step>
<step id = "bvibebi"><para>When you are done, click <guimenu>Apply</guimenu> to
apply your changes.</para></step>
<step id = "bvibebj"><para>Click <guimenu>OK</guimenu> to close
the iFolder Preferences dialog box.</para></step></procedure></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "firewall"><title>Configuring Local
Firewall Settings for iFolder Traffic</title>
<para>If you use a local firewall, you must set your firewall to
allow iFolder to choose a local dynamic port or configure a local
static port for the iFolder client to communicate locally (the same
computer) with Mono&reg; XSP Server. iFolder uses Mono XSP
Web services to communicate via HTTP or HTTPS (SSL, default) with
the Novell iFolder enterprise servers where you have iFolder accounts. The
iFolder administrator configures iFolder services that determine
whether communications use HTTP or HTTPS in your environment.</para>
<para>Your firewall does not block traffic between Mono XSP and
the Novell iFolder enterprise server because Mono XSP uses the standard
HTTP or HTTPS ports for traffic. However, if you block the traffic
between the client and Mono XSP, the client has no way to communicate
with the server. You cannot log in to your iFolder account and synchronize
iFolder data.</para>
<para>Initially, the iFolder configuration does not specify a particular
port to use for client-to-Mono XSP communications. When iFolder
first runs, it opens an available local port to listen for requests
from Mono XSP and to send data to the server via Mono XSP. It writes
the port number to a configuration file and uses this port thereafter
unless the port is not available whenever iFolder starts. If the
port is in use by another application, iFolder selects a different
available port, re-configures the port in the configuration file,
and uses the new port thereafter. For example, if iFolder is down
and another application takes the port, iFolder must select and
configure a different port to use when you restart iFolder.</para>
<bridgehead id = "bw4di5b">Using a Local Dynamic Port</bridgehead>
<para>If you use a local firewall on your computer, the firewall
should detect the local traffic between the iFolder and Mono XSP
server whenever iFolder contacts the server to synchronize its list
of users and iFolder data. Select <guimenu>Allow</guimenu> to permit
the iFolder traffic for this session. If you allow the traffic permanently,
your firewall should not remind you again, and you can avoid receiving
the pop-up alerts whenever iFolder starts.</para>
<para>If you block the iFolder-to-Mono XSP traffic, your firewall
prevents you from connecting with the iFolder server and you cannot
synchronize your files. iFolder does not detect that traffic is
blocked by the firewall; it reports only that it cannot connect
to your account on the iFolder server.</para>
<bridgehead id = "bw4di5c">Using a Local Static Port</bridgehead>
<para>You can optionally add the Web Service Port Range parameter
in the Service Manager section of the <filename>Simias.config</filename> file
to allow Mono XSP Server to use a static port or a range of ports
for this local traffic. This port or range of ports can then be
opened in the firewall to allow communications for Mono XSP. </para>
<para>You can find <filename>Simias.config</filename> in the following
locations:</para>
<informaltable frame = "topbot" rowsep = "0"><tgroup cols = "2">
<colspec colnum = "1" colname = "1" colwidth = "1.111in"/>
<colspec colnum = "2" colname = "2" colwidth = "4.722in"/>
<thead>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "bwejkc4">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Operating System</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Location of the Simias.config File</para></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "bwejkc5">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Linux</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para><filename>&sol;home&sol;<replaceable>username</replaceable>&sol;.local&sol;share&sol;simias&sol;Simias.config</filename></para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "bwejlap">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Windows</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para><filename>C:&bsol;Documents and Settings&bsol;<replaceable>username</replaceable>&bsol;Local
Settings&bsol;Application Data&bsol;simias&bsol;Simias.config</filename></para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "bwejkc6">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Macintosh</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para><filename>&sol;Users&sol;<replaceable>username</replaceable>&sol;.local&sol;share&sol;simias&sol;Simias.config</filename></para></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup></informaltable>
<para>Add the Web Service Port Range Setting to the Service Manager
section of the <filename>Simias.config</filename> file. For example:</para>
<screen>
&lt;configuration>
</screen>
<screen>
  &lt;section name&equals;"ServiceManager">
</screen>
<screen>
    &lt;setting name&equals;"WebServicePortRange" value&equals;"<replaceable>monoxsp&lowbar;port</replaceable>" &sol;>   
</screen>
<screen>
  &lt;&sol;section>
</screen>
<screen>
&lt;&sol;configuration>
</screen>
<para>Replace <replaceable>monoxsp&lowbar;port</replaceable> with
a port number or range of port numbers:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>Specify a value of a single four-digit
port number (such as 1234) to use a single static port. For example:</para>
<screen>
&lt;setting name&equals;"WebServicePortRange" value&equals;"<replaceable>1234</replaceable>" &sol;>
</screen></listitem>
<listitem><para>Specify a range of ports (such as &ldquo;1234-1236&rdquo;)
to use any available port in the specified range of ports. For example:</para>
<screen>
&lt;setting name&equals;"WebServicePortRange" value&equals;"<replaceable>1234-1236</replaceable>" &sol;>
</screen></listitem></itemizedlist>
<para>To configure your system to use a specific port or range of
ports:</para>
<procedure id = "b25pz8x"><step id = "bw4v93e"><para>Configure your
firewall to allow traffic for the port or range of ports you want
to use for iFolder traffic.</para>
<para>See your firewall&rsquo;s documentation for information
on how to open a port in the firewall.</para></step>
<step id = "bw4v6ou"><para>Stop the iFolder client by right-clicking
the iFolder icon, then selecting <guimenu>Exit</guimenu>.</para></step>
<step id = "bw4v6r7"><para>Modify the <filename>Simias.config</filename> file
by adding the <guimenu>Web Service Port Range</guimenu> parameter
to the <guimenu>Service Manager</guimenu> section.</para></step>
<step id = "bw4vbz4"><para>Start the iFolder client.</para>
<para>For more information, see <xref linkend = "startclient"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/>.</para></step></procedure></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "virusscan"><title>Configuring Local
Virus Scanner Settings for iFolder Traffic</title>
<para>If you use virus scanning software on your computer, exclude
the <filename>..&bsol;simias&bsol;WorkArea&bsol;</filename> directory
from the virus scan. For example, the location of the <filename>..&bsol;simias&bsol;WorkArea&bsol;</filename> directory
on Windows is <filename>c:&bsol;documents and settings&bsol;<replaceable>username</replaceable>&bsol;local settings&bsol;application
data&bsol;simias&bsol;WorkArea&bsol;.simias.wf.<replaceable>guid</replaceable></filename>. </para>
<para>The <filename>..&bsol;simias&bsol;WorkArea&bsol;</filename> directory
is where iFolder stages files for download from the server. If an
iFolder file has a virus attached and your virus scanning software
scans that virus while the file is in the <filename>..&bsol;simias&bsol;WorkArea</filename> directory,
the virus scanner pops up with a message indicating that a virus
has been found, moves the file to quarantine, then iFolder again
tries to synchronize the file. </para>
<para>Not scanning the WorkArea allows the synchronization to complete;
the infected file is successfully downloaded and moved to the local
iFolder. The virus scanner then detects the infected file in the iFolder
and moves it from that folder to quarantine, protecting the computer
from infection. iFolder detects the deletion of the file and when
the next synchronization begins, iFolder removes the file from the
server and member computers. </para>
<para>However, if the iFolder where the file is downloaded is Read-Only,
the local deletion is not enforced to the server and other member
computers. The virus must be detected elsewhere where permissions allow
changes to be synchronized. The user&rsquo;s virus scanner probably
alerts the user of the virus, so the user should alert other iFolder
members about the virus.</para></sect1></chapter>

<chapter revision = "03/22/06" conformance = "none,doc,yes,4,80"
    lang = "en" id = "myifolders" xml:base = "04_ifolders.xml"><title>Managing
iFolders</title>
<para>An iFolder&trade; is a local directory used to selectively
share and synchronizes files with user-specified members. The iFolder
files are accessible to all members via a host service, such as
a Novell&reg; iFolder&reg; 3.x server. iFolder files can
be modified and read by those with privileges to do so. </para>
<para>This section discusses the following tasks for iFolder:</para>
<itemizedlist role="subtoc"><listitem><para><xref linkend = "locguide"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "typeguide"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "nameconv" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "ificons" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "createifolder"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "sharewith"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "viewhide" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "setupifolder"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "propifolders"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "ifquota" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "sync" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "conflicts"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "reverting"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "movelocation"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "deleting" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem></itemizedlist>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "locguide"><title>Guidelines for Locating
and Using iFolders</title>
<para>Generally, you can locate iFolders anywhere on your local
hard drive whenever you create an iFolder or set up an iFolder that
is shared with you. However, there are some practical and specific limitations.
Consider the following guidelines in locating and using iFolders
on your computer:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>An iFolder&rsquo;s name must be
a unique folder name in the directory where you locate the iFolder.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>An iFolder&rsquo;s name cannot contain the following
invalid characters:</para>
<screen>
&bsol;&sol;:&ast;?"&lt;>&verbar;;
</screen>
<para>For other naming conventions, see <xref linkend = "nameconv"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/>.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>The iFolder must reside on a local hard drive; the
location cannot be on a network drive or non-physical drive.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>An iFolder cannot exist at the root of the hard
drive. </para></listitem>
<listitem><para>An iFolder can be created only from an existing
folder. </para></listitem>
<listitem><para>An iFolder can be created only from a folder where
you have the file system access rights to read and write files.
When you set up a shared iFolder on a computer, you must have the
file system access rights to the folder where you are locating the
iFolder.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>An iFolder cannot contain or reside in a system
folder such as the <filename>C:&bsol;Windows</filename> directory
or a Linux or Macintosh system volume.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>An iFolder cannot contain or reside in an applications
folder such as the Program Files folder.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>The iFolder cannot contain or reside in the iFolder
metadata folder. The default location of the metadata folder is
as follows:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><formalpara id = "bx09dxu"><title>Linux: </title>
<para>In your home folder in the <filename>.local&bsol;share</filename> subdirectory</para></formalpara></listitem>
<listitem><formalpara id = "bx09ffv"><title>Windows: </title>
<para>In the <filename>C:&bsol;Documents and Settings&bsol;<replaceable>WindowsLogonUsername</replaceable>&bsol;Local
Settings&bsol;Application Data&bsol;simias</filename> directory</para></formalpara></listitem>
<listitem><formalpara id = "bx09ffw"><title>Macintosh: </title>
<para>In your home folder in the <filename>.local&bsol;share</filename> subdirectory</para></formalpara></listitem></itemizedlist></listitem>
<listitem><para>An iFolder cannot contain or reside in other iFolders,
including your Novell iFolder 2.1x iFolder.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Although you can log in to more than one iFolder
account at a time, an iFolder can be associated with only one iFolder
account. You cannot synchronize one iFolder against multiple accounts.
When you create an iFolder, the iFolder can be shared only with
other users that are provisioned in the same iFolder server&sol;domain.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>When multiple users share a computer, the local
copies of your iFolders are private to your storage space on the
disk if the file system supports privacy features, and if you configure
your system to use them.</para>
<para>On Windows, NTFS includes built-in security features such
as file and folder permissions and the Encrypting File System (EFS),
which is the technology used to store encrypted files on NTFS volumes.
These security features are not supported on FAT32 file systems.
Make sure the local login identities for users (other than the Administrator
identity, of course) do not have the Administrator rights or equivalent.
The Administrator user has access to all files and directories on
the computer. For shared computers where privacy and security are
essential for each user, the users can encrypt their local copy
of iFolder data with EFS or a third-party file system encryption.</para>
<para>Linux and Macintosh file systems are designed for multi-user
environments. File permissions allow you to control access for the
user, groups, and others. A user&rsquo;s personal files are typically set
with full permissions for the user and no access for the groups
and others settings. </para>
<para>If you store iFolders locally on a FAT32 volume on Linux,
it requires special handling because FAT32 file systems are not
POSIX compliant. For information, see <xref linkend = "fat32mtpt"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/>.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>If users of the same computer share iFolders, multiple
copies of the iFolder can exist on the device, with a copy for each
user that downloads it from the server. Different local login identities
cannot share a single location for the shared iFolders.</para></listitem></itemizedlist></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "typeguide"><title>Guidelines for File
Types and Sizes to Not Synchronize</title>
<para>When the iFolder client is used with Novell iFolder 3.<replaceable>x</replaceable>,
your iFolder administrator might specify file type restrictions
and maximum file size restrictions at the system, user, or iFolder
level. Your account might also be restricted in the amount of space
you can use for the data in the iFolders you own. When you participate
in other iFolders, the space consumed on the server is counted against the
owner of that iFolder.</para>
<para>Some file types are not good candidates for synchronization,
such as operating system files, hidden files created by a file manager,
or databases that are implemented as a collection of linked files.
You might include only key file types used for your business, or
exclude files that are likely unrelated to business, such as <filename>.mp3</filename> files. </para>
<bridgehead id = "bweu18w">Operating System Files</bridgehead>
<para>You should not convert system directories to iFolders. Most
system files change infrequently and it is better to keep an image
file of your basic system and key software than to attempt to synchronize those
files to the server.</para>
<bridgehead id = "bwepcty">Hidden Files</bridgehead>
<para>If your file system uses hidden files to track display preferences,
your administrator might restrict those file types to exclude them
from being synchronized on your system. Usually, hidden files are relevant
only to the particular computer where they were created, and they
change every time the file or directory is accessed. You do not
need to keep these files, and synchronizing them results in repeated
file conflict errors. </para>
<para>For example, iFolder automatically excludes two hidden file
manager files called <filename>thumbs.db</filename> and <filename>.DS&lowbar;Store</filename>.</para>
<bridgehead id = "bwepcz5">Database Files</bridgehead>
<para>iFolder synchronizes individual files or the changed portions
of individual files; it does not synchronize files as a set. If
you have a database file that is implemented as a collection of
linked files, do not try to synchronize them in an iFolder.</para>
<para>Do not try to synchronize your GroupWise&reg; data by
making the GroupWise archive, cache, or remote directories into
iFolders. If you do this, the GroupWise data files become corrupted
after synchronizing the file a few times. GroupWise needs the files
in the archive to be maintained as a set of files.</para></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "nameconv"><title>Naming Conventions
for an iFolder and Its Folders and Files</title>
<para>The iFolder client imposes naming conventions that consider
the collective restrictions of the Linux, Windows, and Macintosh
file systems. An iFolder, folder, or file must have a valid name
that complies with the naming conventions before it can be synchronized.</para>
<para>Use the following naming conventions for your iFolders and
the folders and files in them:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>iFolder supports the <ulink
    url = "http://www.unicode.org">Unicode&thrdmrk;</ulink> character
set with UTF-8 encoding. </para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Do not use the following invalid characters in the
names of iFolders or in the names of folders and files in them:</para>
<screen>
&bsol;&sol;:&ast;?"&lt;>&verbar;;
</screen>
<para>iFolder creates a name conflict if you use the invalid characters
in a file or folder name. The conflict must be resolved before the
file or folder can be synchronized.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>The maximum name length for a single path component
is 255 bytes. For filenames, the maximum length includes the dot
(.) and file extension.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Names of iFolders, folders, and files are case insensitive;
however, case is preserved. If filenames differ only by case, iFolder
creates a name conflict. The conflict must be resolved before the
file or folder can be synchronized.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>If you create iFolders on a FAT32 file system on
Linux, avoid naming files in all uppercase characters. The VFAT
or FAT32 file handling on Linux automatically changes the filenames that
are all uppercase characters and meet the MS-DOS 8.3 file format
from all uppercase characters to all lowercase characters. This
creates synchronization problems for those files if the iFolder
is set with the Read Only access right.</para>
<remark>(Bug 84722, Russ Young, Last updated: July 29, 2005)</remark></listitem></itemizedlist></sect1>
<sect1 id = "ificons"><title>Understanding iFolder Icons</title>
<para>The following table describes iFolder icons and related tasks.</para>
<table id = "b40i4d6" frame = "topbot" rowsep = "1" pgwide = "0">
<title>Description of iFolder Icons</title><tgroup cols = "2">
<colspec colnum = "1" colname = "1" colwidth = "0.972in"/>
<colspec colnum = "2" colname = "2" colwidth = "4.861in"/>
<thead>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b40i8bp">
<entry colname = "1"><para>iFolder Icon</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Description</para></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b40i8bq">
<entry colname = "1"><mediaobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder24.png" width="" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder24.png"
width="" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>The iFolder Application icon is displayed
in the desktop Applications menu for the <guimenu>iFolder 3 Client</guimenu>. </para>
<para>When iFolder is running, the iFolder application icon also
appears in the Notification area of the desktop taskbar. Right-click
it for a menu of possible tasks, including iFolder browser, Account
Settings, Synchronization Log, Preferences, and Help.</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b40ijyj">
<entry colname = "1"><mediaobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder-upload22.png" width="" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder-upload22.png"
width="" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>The iFolder Upload icon is displayed
in the iFolder browser under <guimenu>iFolders on This Computer</guimenu> if
there are no iFolders are on the computer under your current local
login identity. </para>
<para>You can create a new iFolder or convert an existing folder
to an iFolder. If you have multiple accounts, you must specify which
account to use; an iFolder can belong to only one account. For information,
see <xref linkend = "createifolder" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/>.</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b40jpkh">
<entry colname = "1"><mediaobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder-download22.png" width="" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder-download22.png"
width="" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>The iFolder Download icon is displayed
in the iFolder browser under <guimenu>iFolders on This Computer</guimenu> if
no iFolders are on the computer under your current local login identity. </para>
<para>The iFolder Download icon is displayed under <guimenu>iFolders
on &lt;the iFolder Account Server></guimenu> when an iFolder is
available to you on the server, but you have not downloaded it to
this computer.</para>
<para>You can download any combination of iFolders from different
accounts to the local computer. For information, see <xref
    linkend = "setupifolder" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/>.</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b40i8br">
<entry colname = "1"><mediaobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder32.png" width="22.00pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder32.png"
width="22.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>The iFolder emblem (green &ldquo;i&rdquo;)
appears on iFolders whenever the iFolder application is running
for iFolders viewed in a file manager, on the desktop, or in the
iFolder browser.</para>
<para>When iFolder is not running, iFolders appear as normal folders <inlinemediaobject><imageobject
role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/folder_16.gif" width="11.00pt"
format="GIF"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/folder_16.gif"
width="11.00pt" format="gif"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> when
viewed in the file manager or on the desktop. The iFolder browser
is not available when iFolder is not running. </para>
<para>It is a good practice to organize your local collection of
iFolders in a separate directory that contains only iFolders. This
makes it easy to remember which folders are iFolders even when iFolder
is not running and providing icons to mark them as iFolders.</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b40i8bs">
<entry colname = "1"><mediaobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder-warning22.png" width="" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder-warning22.png"
width="" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>The iFolder Warning icon indicates that
the server is unavailable. iFolder is running but you are not connected
to the iFolder server. Possible causes are:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>You are not logged in to the iFolder
account. For information, see <xref linkend = "login"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/>.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>The account is disabled on the client side; that
is, the <guimenu>Automatically connect</guimenu> parameter is disabled.
For information, see <guimenu>Automatically connect</guimenu> in <xref
    linkend = "accountdetails" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/>.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>The server is down or your account is disabled on
the server side. Contact your iFolder administrator for assistance.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Your firewall is blocking iFolder traffic. For information
to resolve this problem, see <xref linkend = "firewall"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/>.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Your network connection is down. Check your local
network settings.</para></listitem></itemizedlist></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b40jpkg">
<entry colname = "1"><mediaobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder-waiting22.png" width="" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder-waiting22.png"
width="" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>The iFolder Waiting to Synchronize icon
indicates that the iFolder contains files to be synchronized with
the server, and the synchronization process has not yet begun. </para>
<para>iFolder synchronizes one iFolder at a time, and queues the
synchronization tasks. To make sure that files in this local iFolder
are synchronized with the files on the server, wait to shut down
iFolder until the synchronization begins and completes successfully, as
indicated by the changes in the icon.</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b41ph8h">
<entry colname = "1"><mediaobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder-sync22.png" width="" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder-sync22.png"
width="" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>The iFolder Synchronizing icon indicates
that files in the iFolder are currently being synchronized with
the server.</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b41ph8i">
<entry colname = "1"><mediaobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder-error22.png" width="" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder-error22.png"
width="" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>The iFolder Error icon indicates that
one or more files in the iFolder have not been synchronized because
there is a conflict between the local copy and server copy of a file.
Resolve the conflict by indicating which version of the file to
keep.</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b40jtqi">
<entry colname = "1"><mediaobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder-user-owner16.png" width="" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder-user-owner16.png"
width="" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>In the Sharing dialog box, the iFolder
Owner User icon indicates that the user owns the shared iFolder. </para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "b40jxou">
<entry colname = "1"><mediaobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder-user-current16.png" width="" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder-user-current16.png"
width="" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>In the Sharing dialog box, the iFolder
Current User icon indicates that the user is currently managing
the iFolder. If the current user is the owner, the Owner User icon
is displayed instead.</para></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup></table></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "createifolder"><title>Creating and
Uploading an iFolder</title>
<para>You can create an iFolder by converting an existing folder
that satisfies the following guidelines: </para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para><xref linkend = "locguide"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "nameconv" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem></itemizedlist>
<para>If the folder does not exist, you can browse to a location
and create the new folder as part of the process. </para>
<para>Within the iFolder, you can set up any subdirectory structure
that suits your personal or corporate work habits. The subdirectory
structure is constant across all member iFolders. Each workstation can
specify a different parent directory for the shared iFolder.</para>
<para>You can create iFolders with a file manager or with the iFolder
browser, which is available in the client application. Use the following
methods to create an iFolder</para>
<sect2 id = "bwembx5"><title>Creating iFolders in a File Manager</title>
<procedure id = "b25pz8y"><step id = "bq6lwlg"><para>Use the file
manager to navigate to the folder you want to convert to an iFolder,
then select the folder.</para></step>
<step id = "bq6lwlh"><para>Use one of the following methods:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>Right-click the folder icon, then
click <guimenu>Convert to an iFolder.</guimenu></para></listitem>
<listitem><para>In the toolbar, click <menuchoice><guimenu>File</guimenu>
<guimenu>Convert to an iFolder</guimenu></menuchoice>.</para></listitem></itemizedlist>
<para>The folder icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject role="description"><phrase>Folder
Icon</phrase></textobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/folder_16.gif"
width="11pt" format="GIF"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/folder_16.gif"
width="11pt" format="gif"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> changes
to a folder with an overlay of the iFolder emblem (green &ldquo;i&rdquo;) <inlinemediaobject><textobject
role="description"><phrase>iFolder Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject
role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder32.png" width="11pt"
format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder32.png"
width="11pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject>.</para></step>
<step id = "bx19z0q"><para>If the <literal>iFolder Created</literal> message
appears, do one of the following:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>Click <guimenu>Close</guimenu> to
dismiss the message.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Select <guimenu>Do Not Show This Message Again </guimenu>to
disable future notifications, then click <guimenu>Close</guimenu> to
dismiss the message.</para>
<para>If you later decide that you want to get confirmation messages,
go to iFolder Preferences, select <guimenu>Show Confirmation Dialog
When Creating iFolders</guimenu>, then click <guimenu>OK</guimenu>.</para></listitem></itemizedlist></step></procedure></sect2>
<sect2 id = "bwemc36"><title>Creating iFolders in the iFolder Browser</title>
<procedure id = "b25pz8z"><step id = "bv2gxbu"><para>In the Notification
area, use one of the following methods to open the iFolder browser:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>Click the iFolder application icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject
role="description"><phrase>iFolder Application Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject
role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png" width="11.00pt"
format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject>.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Right-click the iFolder application icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject
role="description"><phrase>iFolder Application Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject
role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png" width="11.00pt"
format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject>,
then click <guimenu>iFolders</guimenu>.</para></listitem></itemizedlist></step>
<step id = "bv2gxbv"><para>Click <guimenu>Upload a folder</guimenu>.</para></step>
<step id = "bv2gwvt"><para>Specify the iFolder account you want
to use for this iFolder.</para>
<para>If you have multiple iFolder accounts, the default account
is listed first. Use the drop-down list to select a different account.</para></step>
<step id = "bv2guwr"><para>In the browser, navigate to the directory
where you want to create an iFolder.</para></step>
<step id = "bv2gv55"><para>Select the normal folder you want to
make an iFolder, using one of these methods:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>If the normal folder exists, select
the folder, then click <guimenu>OK</guimenu>.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>If the normal folder does not exist, click <guimenu>Make
New Folder</guimenu> to create it, select the newly created folder,
then click <guimenu>OK</guimenu>.</para></listitem></itemizedlist></step>
<step id = "bwb5ss4"><para>Click <guimenu>OK</guimenu>.</para>
<para>The iFolder appears in the <guimenu>iFolders on This Computer</guimenu> list.</para></step>
<step id = "bwb5tng"><para>If the <literal>iFolder Created</literal> message
appears, do one of the following:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>Click <guimenu>Close</guimenu> to
dismiss the message.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Select <guimenu>Do Not Show This Message Again</guimenu> to
disable future notifications, then click <guimenu>Close</guimenu> to
dismiss the message.</para>
<para>If you later decide that you want to get confirmation messages,
go to <guimenu>iFolder Preferences</guimenu>, select <guimenu>Show
Confirmation Dialog When Creating iFolders</guimenu>, then click <guimenu>OK</guimenu>.</para></listitem></itemizedlist></step></procedure></sect2>
<sect2 id = "fat32mtpt"><title>Creating iFolders on a FAT32 Mount
Point (Linux)</title>
<para>On Linux, iFolder supports creating and using iFolders on
a mount point for a FAT32 file system. Before you can create new
iFolders or set up shared iFolders on a FAT32 volume on your Linux computer,
the iFolder user must own the FAT32 mount point where you want to
store the iFolders, and the <filename>&sol;etc&sol;fstab</filename> file
must explicitly identify the iFolder user&rsquo;s local user
ID for the mount point. </para>
<important>
<para>This is required because FAT32 does not support file permissions.
Any other file system that does not support permissions has the
same issue.</para></important>
<para>For dual boot systems, you can access the data in iFolders
as normal folders from the system where the folder is not set up
as an iFolder. If you set up the folder as an iFolder on both platforms,
the data set is stored in two different iFolders on the server,
which consumes double your allocated server disk resources.</para>
<para>Because the FAT32 file system does not support POSIX&ast; file
system permissions, make sure the iFolder user is the local owner
of the mount point. Modify the &sol;etc&sol;fstab file
to set the user ID (UID) parameter of the user&rsquo;s local
login identity to the iFolder user who creates iFolders on that
mount point.</para>
<procedure id = "b25pz90"><step id = "bwenpgg"><para>Log in to your
computer as the root user.</para></step>
<step id = "bwen6om"><para>Create the directory where you want to
mount the FAT32 file system. At a command prompt, enter</para>
<screen>
mkdir &sol;home&sol;<replaceable>username</replaceable>&sol;<replaceable>fsmount</replaceable>
</screen>
<para>Replace <filename><replaceable>username</replaceable></filename> with
the username of the user who plans to use the FAT32 drive for iFolders.
Replace <filename><replaceable>fsmount</replaceable></filename> with
the directory name you want to use as the mount point. For example,
if the username is <filename><replaceable>jsmith</replaceable></filename> and
the directory name is <filename><replaceable>fat32mntpt</replaceable></filename> for
a FAT32 drive or partition, enter</para>
<screen>
mkdir &sol;home&sol;jsmith&sol;fat32mntpt
</screen></step>
<step id = "bwemec8"><para>Mount the FAT32 drive at the desired
mount point. At a command prompt, enter</para>
<screen>
mount -t vfat &sol;dev&sol;<replaceable>hda1</replaceable> &sol;home&sol;<replaceable>username</replaceable>&sol;<replaceable>fsmount </replaceable>
</screen>
<para>Replace <filename>&sol;dev&sol;<replaceable>hda1</replaceable></filename> with
the device or partition name of the non-Linux device. Replace <filename><replaceable>username</replaceable></filename> with
the username of the iFolder user. Replace <filename><replaceable>fsmount</replaceable></filename> with
the directory name you want to use as the mount point. </para>
<para>Continuing the example, where the FAT32 file system (<literal>vfat</literal>)
is on the <filename>hda4</filename> device (<filename><replaceable>&sol;dev&sol;hda4</replaceable></filename>),
the username is <filename><replaceable>jsmith</replaceable></filename>,
and the mount point directory is <filename>&sol;home&sol;<replaceable>jsmith</replaceable>&sol;<replaceable>fat32mntpt</replaceable></filename>,
enter</para>
<screen>
mount -t vfat &sol;dev&sol;hda4 &sol;home&sol;jsmith&sol;fat32mntpt
</screen></step>
<step id = "bwemszm"><para>Edit the <filename>&sol;etc&sol;fstab</filename> file
by adding the <literal>uid&equals;username</literal> parameter
of the iFolder user on the line that defines the FAT32 mount point.</para>
<screen>
&sol;dev&sol;<replaceable>hda1</replaceable>  &sol;home&sol;<replaceable>username</replaceable>&sol;<replaceable>fsmount</replaceable>  <replaceable>vfat</replaceable>  uid&equals;<replaceable>username</replaceable>
</screen>
<para>Continuing the example, modify <filename>&sol;etc&sol;fstab</filename> file
by adding <literal>uid&equals;jsmith</literal> to the mount point:</para>
<screen>
&sol;dev&sol;hda4  &sol;home&sol;jsmith&sol;fat32mntpt  vfat  uid&equals;jsmith
</screen></step></procedure></sect2></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "sharewith"><title>Sharing an iFolder</title>
<para>You can share an iFolder with multiple users. This section
discusses the following tasks:</para>
<itemizedlist role="subtoc"><listitem><para><xref linkend = "bv2hnvt"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "b41tbcf" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "bq6lwm0" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "bq6lwma" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "bq6lwmr" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "b47q8t9" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem></itemizedlist>
<sect2 id = "bv2hnvt"><title>Understanding User Access Rights</title>
<para>The following table describes the capabilities associated
with each level of access for users.</para>
<table id = "b4031ex" frame = "topbot" rowsep = "1" pgwide = "0">
<title>Capabilities of iFolder Owners and Members Based on Their
User Access Rights </title><tgroup cols = "5">
<colspec colnum = "1" colname = "1" colwidth = "2.500in"/>
<colspec colnum = "2" colname = "2" colwidth = "0.833in"/>
<colspec colnum = "3" colname = "3" colwidth = "0.833in"/>
<colspec colnum = "4" colname = "4" colwidth = "0.833in"/>
<colspec colnum = "5" colname = "5" colwidth = "0.833in"/>
<thead>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4033q0">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Capabilities</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Owner</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>Member with Full Control</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Member with Read&sol;Write</para></entry>
<entry colname = "5"><para>Member with Read Only</para></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4033q1">
<entry colname = "1"><para>With an enterprise server, the space consumed
by the iFolder on the server is charged against the user&rsquo;s
quota</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>No</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>No</para></entry>
<entry colname = "5"><para>No</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4033q2">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Transfer ownership to another member whose
state is iFolder User </para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>No</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>No</para></entry>
<entry colname = "5"><para>No</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4035im">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Set a quota for the iFolder</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>No</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>No</para></entry>
<entry colname = "5"><para>No</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4035in">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Make the iFolder available to other users (sharing)</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>No</para></entry>
<entry colname = "5"><para>No</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4035io">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Make the iFolder unavailable to other
users (stop sharing)</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>Yes, except the owner</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>No</para></entry>
<entry colname = "5"><para>No</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4035ip">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Assign iFolder access rights for other
users</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>Yes, except the owner</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>No</para></entry>
<entry colname = "5"><para>No</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4035iq">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Read directories and files in the iFolder </para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "5"><para>Yes</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4035ir">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Add, modify, or delete directories and
files in the iFolder</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "5"><para>No</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4035is">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Rename directories and files in an iFolder</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "5"><para>Yes</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4035it">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Rename the iFolder</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>No</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>No</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>No</para></entry>
<entry colname = "5"><para>No</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4035iu">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Set up an iFolder on multiple computers</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "5"><para>Yes</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4035iv">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Revert an iFolder (do not participate
on a local computer)</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "5"><para>Yes</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4035iw">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Delete an available iFolder to decline participating</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "5"><para>Yes</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "b4035ix">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Delete the iFolder and delete the iFolder and
its files from the server (make it a normal folder again and no
longer share it with others)</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Yes</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>No</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>No</para></entry>
<entry colname = "5"><para>No</para></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup></table></sect2>
<sect2 id = "b41tbcf"><title>Accessing the Sharing Tab</title>
<para>You can manage membership for the iFolder from the Sharing
tab in the iFolder Properties dialog box.</para>
<procedure id = "b41tmw0"><step id = "b41tmw1"><para>If iFolder
is not running, start iFolder.</para></step>
<step id = "b41tmw2"><para>Do one of the following to open the iFolder
Properties dialog box to the <guimenu>Sharing</guimenu> tab.</para>
<informalfigure pgwide = "0"><mediaobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/if3_sharing_a.png" width="180pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/if3_sharing_a.png"
width="180pt" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></informalfigure>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>In a file manager, right-click the
iFolder you want to share, then select <guimenu>Share with</guimenu>.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>In the iFolder browser, select the iFolder, then
select <guimenu>Share with</guimenu>.</para></listitem></itemizedlist></step></procedure></sect2>
<sect2 id = "bq6lwm0"><title>Adding a User to an iFolder</title>
<procedure id = "b25pz92"><step id = "b41tjp8"><para>On the Sharing
tab, click <guimenu>Add</guimenu> to open the Select User dialog
box.</para></step>
<step id = "bv2hqlb"><para>From the list of users, select one or
more users by adding them to the <guimenu>Selected Users</guimenu> list,
then click <guimenu>OK</guimenu>.</para>
<para>It can take several seconds for the invitations to synchronize
up to the server.</para></step>
<step id = "bv2hqlc"><para>On the Sharing tab, select one or more
users who you want to assign the same access right. </para></step>
<step id = "b41tpyv"><para>Click <guimenu>Access</guimenu>, select
the <guimenu>Full Control</guimenu>, <guimenu>Read&sol;Write</guimenu>,
or <guimenu>Read Only</guimenu> access right, then click <guimenu>OK</guimenu>.</para></step>
<step id = "bx3vxly"><para>Repeat the previous steps until you have
invited all the desired users to share the iFolder and set their
access rights.</para></step>
<step id = "bv2hqld"><para>Click <guimenu>Apply</guimenu>, then
click <guimenu>OK</guimenu> to close the iFolder Properties window.</para></step></procedure></sect2>
<sect2 id = "bq6lwma"><title>Modifying User Access Rights</title>
<para>As the working relationships and status of members of an iFolder
change, you might need to change a user&rsquo;s access right
for the iFolder. For example, you might want to give a trusted user
the Full Control right for the iFolder.</para>
<procedure id = "b25pz93"><step id = "bv2hncw"><para>On the Sharing
tab, select one or more users who you want to have the same access
right.</para></step>
<step id = "bv2hoj5"><para>Select <guimenu>Access</guimenu>, then
specify the <guimenu>Full Control</guimenu>, <guimenu>Read&sol;Write</guimenu>,
or <guimenu>Read Only</guimenu> right.</para>
<para>When you first invite a user to participate, the <guimenu>Make
this user the owner of the iFolder </guimenu>option is disabled
(dimmed) in the Access dialog box. If you intend to make the new
user the owner, you must wait until the user&rsquo;s state changes
from <guimenu>Invited User</guimenu> to <guimenu>iFolder User</guimenu>,
then you can transfer ownership.</para>
<informalfigure pgwide = "0"><mediaobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/if3_ifcr_share-accessro_a.png" width="100.00pt"
format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/if3_ifcr_share-accessro_a.png"
width="100.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></informalfigure></step>
<step id = "bv2hpae"><para>Click <guimenu>OK</guimenu>, then click <guimenu>OK</guimenu> to
close the iFolder Properties window.</para></step></procedure></sect2>
<sect2 id = "bq6lwmr"><title>Removing a User from an iFolder</title>
<para>To unshare an iFolder, you must remove a user as a member
of an iFolder. The iFolder on the user&rsquo;s workstation becomes
a normal folder. A copy of the data remains on the former member&rsquo;s workstation,
but the files are no longer synchronized with the shared iFolder.</para>
<procedure id = "b25pz95"><step id = "bv2hug0"><para>On the Sharing
tab, select one or more users from the list.</para></step>
<step id = "bv2hug1"><para>Click <guimenu>Remove</guimenu>, click <guimenu>Apply</guimenu>,
then click <guimenu>OK</guimenu>.</para></step></procedure></sect2>
<sect2 id = "b47q8t9"><title>Transferring Ownership to an iFolder
User</title>
<para>The owner of an iFolder can transfer ownership of the iFolder
to another member whose state is iFolder User. After the transfer,
the original owner becomes a member with the Read&sol;Write
right, and the space consumed by the iFolder is charged against
the new owner. </para>
<procedure id = "b47q8ta"><step id = "b47q70j"><para>In a file manager
or the iFolder browser, right-click the iFolder you want to transfer,
then select <guimenu>Share With</guimenu> to open the iFolder&rsquo;s
Properties dialog box to the <guimenu>Sharing</guimenu> tab.</para></step>
<step id = "b47q8tb"><para>From the list of users, select the iFolder
User who is to be the new owner, then click <guimenu>Access</guimenu>.</para></step>
<step id = "b47q70k"><para>Select <guimenu>Make this user the owner
of this iFolder</guimenu>.</para>
<para>The <guimenu>Make this user the owner of the iFolder </guimenu>option
is disabled (dimmed) in the Access dialog box if the user&rsquo;s
state is <guimenu>Invited User</guimenu>. In this case, exit the
dialog box, wait until the user&rsquo;s state changes from <guimenu>Invited
User</guimenu> to <guimenu>iFolder User</guimenu>, then repeat the
preceding steps to transfer ownership.</para></step>
<step id = "b47qbju"><para>Click <guimenu>OK</guimenu>, then click <guimenu>OK</guimenu> to
close the iFolder Properties window.</para></step></procedure></sect2></sect1>
<sect1 id = "viewhide"><title>Viewing and Hiding Available iFolders</title>
<para>You can decide which iFolders you want to download to each
of your computers. If iFolders are available to you on the server
that you have not downloaded, they are listed in the iFolder browser under
the related account. </para>
<para>To view the available iFolders in the iFolder browser, click <guimenu>View
Available iFolders</guimenu>.</para>
<para>To hide the available iFolders in the iFolder browser, click <guimenu>Hide
Available iFolders</guimenu>.</para></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "setupifolder"><title>Downloading an
Available iFolder</title>
<para>When others share iFolders with you, the iFolders appear with
the iFolder Download icon <inlinemediaobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder-download22.png" width="11pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder-download22.png"
width="11pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> under <guimenu>iFolders
on iFolder Server Name </guimenu>in your iFolder browser, where
the <replaceable>iFolder Server Name</replaceable> is the name of
the server for that account. To participate in the shared iFolder
on your computer, you can download the iFolder.</para>
<para>If the <guimenu>Notify of Shared iFolders </guimenu>parameter
is enabled, iFolder announces the availability of shared iFolders
with a balloon pop-up message in the Notification area. You can
click the balloon to set up the iFolder at that time, or close the
balloon to download the iFolder later.</para>
<figure pgwide = "0" id = "b40hlcu"><title>Example Notification
of a Shared iFolder</title>
<mediaobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/if_notify_a.png"
width="202.5pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/if_notify_a.png"
width="202.5pt" format="png"/></imageobject></mediaobject></figure>
<bridgehead id = "b422qwt">Guidelines</bridgehead>
<para>The local iFolder location must satisfy the following guidelines: </para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para><xref linkend = "locguide"
    xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem>
<listitem><para><xref linkend = "nameconv" xrefstyle = "SectTitleOnPage"/></para></listitem></itemizedlist>
<bridgehead id = "b422r2k">Downloading an iFolder</bridgehead>
<procedure id = "b25pz97"><step id = "bv2ht17"><para>Right-click
the iFolder application icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject role="description"><phrase>iFolder
Application Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png" width="11.00pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject>,
then click <guimenu>iFolders</guimenu> to open the iFolder browser.</para></step>
<step id = "bv2ht18"><para>In the list of iFolders, select the available
iFolder, then click <guimenu>Download an iFolder</guimenu>.</para></step>
<step id = "bv2ht19"><para>If you are not logged in to the account,
log in with your username and password, then click <guimenu>Connect</guimenu>.</para></step>
<step id = "bwb62m2"><para>Browse to the location where you want
to create a local iFolder.</para></step>
<step id = "bwb63b7"><para>Click <guimenu>OK</guimenu> twice.</para></step></procedure></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "propifolders"><title>Viewing and Configuring
Properties of an iFolder</title>
<para>Use the iFolders Properties page to view and configure the
following information about a selected iFolder.</para>
<para>The following parameters report the disk space used on the
server:</para>
<table id = "b403606" frame = "topbot" rowsep = "1" pgwide = "0">
<title>Storage Parameters for iFolders Stored on the iFolder Server</title>
<tgroup cols = "2">
<colspec colnum = "1" colname = "1" colwidth = "1.667in"/>
<colspec colnum = "2" colname = "2" colwidth = "4.167in"/>
<thead>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4038dc">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Parameter</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Description</para></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4038dd">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Available</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>The total amount of server disk space
currently available for files or directories in the selected iFolder.
The value is equal to the quota minus the used space.</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4038de">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Used</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>The total amount of server disk space
currently consumed by all files and directories in the selected
iFolder.</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "b4038df">
<entry colname = "1"><para>One of the following:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para><guimenu>Set Quota</guimenu> </para></listitem>
<listitem><para><guimenu>Quota</guimenu> </para></listitem></itemizedlist></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><itemizedlist><listitem>
<formalpara id = "b4038dg"><title>Set Quota: </title>
<para>If you are the iFolder owner, you can select <guimenu>Set
Quota</guimenu>, then specify a quota in MB for the iFolder.</para></formalpara></listitem>
<listitem><formalpara id = "b4038dh"><title>Quota: </title>
<para>If you are a member, the value reports the total amount of server
disk space allocated to the selected iFolder by the iFolder owner.
If no quota is set, the value is empty or <literal>N&sol;A</literal> (Not
Applicable).</para></formalpara></listitem></itemizedlist></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup></table>
<para>The following parameters report the synchronization status
for the local copy of the iFolder:</para>
<table id = "b40374t" frame = "topbot" rowsep = "1" pgwide = "0">
<title>Synchronization Parameters for iFolders Stored Locally</title>
<tgroup cols = "2">
<colspec colnum = "1" colname = "1" colwidth = "1.667in"/>
<colspec colnum = "2" colname = "2" colwidth = "4.167in"/>
<thead>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4038di">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Parameter</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Description</para></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4038dj">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Last Successful Synchronization</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>The completion time of the most recent
successful synchronization of your local copy of the iFolder with
the iFolder server.</para>
<screen>
mm&sol;dd&sol;yyyy hh:mm:ss
</screen></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4038dk">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Files&sol;Folders to Synchronize</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>The total number of storage items (files
and folders) in the iFolder that need to be synchronized.</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b4038dl">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Automatically Synchronizes Every</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>The synchronization interval for the
iFolder. Specify the value in minutes, hours, or days. </para>
<para>When the iFolder client is used with a Novell iFolder 3.<replaceable>x </replaceable>enterprise
server, the interval cannot override the minimum interval specified
by the iFolder administrator for the server or your account on the
server, but it can override the client-wide synchronization interval.</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "b4038dm">
<entry colname = "1"><para><guimenu>Synchronize Now</guimenu></para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Click the button to initiate a synchronization
on demand.</para></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup></table>
<bridgehead id = "bv2h016">Accessing iFolder Properties from a File
Manager</bridgehead>
<procedure id = "b25pz98"><step id = "bv2h29s"><para>In the file
manager, navigate to the iFolder, then select it.</para></step>
<step id = "bv2h2hg"><para>Right-click the iFolder, then click <menuchoice>
<guimenu>iFolder</guimenu><guimenu>Properties</guimenu></menuchoice>.</para></step></procedure>
<bridgehead id = "bv2h0ey">Accessing iFolder Properties from the
iFolder Browser</bridgehead>
<procedure id = "b25pz99"><step id = "bv2h017"><para>In the Notification
area, right-click the iFolder application icon, then click <guimenu>iFolders</guimenu> to
open the iFolder browser.</para></step>
<step id = "bv2h0o4"><para>In the list of iFolders, select the iFolder,
then click <guimenu>Properties</guimenu>.</para></step></procedure></sect1>
<sect1 id = "ifquota"><title>Setting an iFolder Quota</title>
<para>Setting a quota for an iFolder helps the owner to manage the
space allotted for all of the iFolders the user owns. Member users
of the iFolder can view the quota, but cannot modify it.</para>
<para>On the server, space for your iFolder data is allocated as
it is needed; space is not reserved by the quotas you specify for
each iFolder. It is possible to overbook the quotas so that the
total allocated space can exceed the quota set for your account.
However, the iFolders can individually and collectively grow only
up to the available space for your account. </para>
<para>To enable or modify the quota for an iFolder:</para>
<procedure id = "b47s0j0"><step id = "b47s23v"><para>Open the <guimenu>Properties</guimenu> dialog
box for the iFolder to the <guimenu>General</guimenu> tab.</para></step>
<step id = "b47s0j1"><para>Select <guimenu>Set Quota</guimenu> to
enable the quota.</para></step>
<step id = "b47s54d"><para>Specify the maximum size of the iFolder
in MB. </para></step>
<step id = "b47sfjc"><para>Click <guimenu>Apply</guimenu> to accept
the setting, then click <guimenu>OK</guimenu> to close the Properties
dialog box.</para></step></procedure>
<para>To disable the quota for an iFolder:</para>
<procedure id = "b47sgad"><step id = "b47sgae"><para>Open the <guimenu>Properties</guimenu> dialog
box for the iFolder to the <guimenu>General</guimenu> tab.</para></step>
<step id = "b47sgaf"><para>Deselect <guimenu>Set Quota</guimenu> to
disable the quota.</para></step>
<step id = "b47sgag"><para>Click <guimenu>Apply</guimenu> to accept
the setting, then click <guimenu>OK</guimenu> to close the Properties
dialog box.</para></step></procedure></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "sync"><title>Synchronizing Files</title>
<bridgehead id = "bviejga">Synchronizing Files on Demand</bridgehead>
<procedure id = "b25pz9a"><step id = "bviejgb"><para>In the Notification
area, right-click the iFolder application icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject
role="description"><phrase>iFolder Application Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject
role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png" width="11.00pt"
format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject>,
then click <guimenu>iFolders</guimenu> to open the iFolder browser.</para></step>
<step id = "bviejgc"><para>In the list of iFolders, select the iFolder,
then click <guimenu>Synchronize Now</guimenu>.</para></step></procedure>
<bridgehead id = "bvierhn">Configuring the Synchronization Interval</bridgehead>
<procedure id = "b25pz9b"><step id = "bviete3"><para>In the Notification
area, right-click the iFolder application icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject
role="description"><phrase>iFolder Application Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject
role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png" width="11.00pt"
format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject>,
then select <guimenu>Preferences</guimenu> to open the iFolder Preferences
dialog box to the <guimenu>General</guimenu> tab.</para></step>
<step id = "bviesn8"><para>Do one of the following:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>Select <guimenu>Synchronize</guimenu> to
enable background synchronization.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Deselect <guimenu>Synchronize</guimenu> to disable
synchronization.</para></listitem></itemizedlist></step>
<step id = "bviet4u"><para>If you enable synchronization, specify
the interval for synchronizing files, such as every 1 hour or every
2 days. </para>
<para>When the iFolder client is used with Novell iFolder 3.<replaceable>x</replaceable>,
the minimum system Synchronization Interval, typically every 5 minutes,
is configured by the iFolder administrator. You cannot override
the system minimum. The absolute system minimum is 1 minute.</para></step></procedure></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "conflicts"><title>Resolving File Conflicts</title>
<para>Conflicts can occur between file versions saved at the same
time on different computers, or when a filename differs by case
only. When conflicts occur, the file is stored in the conflict area
and the file is flagged with a status of <guimenu>Name Conflict</guimenu>.
The iFolder Error icon <inlinemediaobject><imageobject role="fo"><imagedata
fileref="graphics/ifolder-error_16.png" width="11.00pt" format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder-error_16.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> is
displayed on the iFolder. If the <guimenu>Notify of conflicts</guimenu> option
is enabled in your iFolder Preferences, an alert is also sent to
the Notification area. You can control the pop-up behavior of Notifications
by setting your preference in the <menuchoice><guimenu>iFolder Preferences</guimenu>
<guimenu>General</guimenu></menuchoice> tab.</para>
<bridgehead id = "bx1b1zs">Version Conflicts</bridgehead>
<para>Version conflicts should be coordinated with other members
before resolving the conflict. Then choose the correct version in
the Conflict Resolution dialog.</para>
<procedure id = "b25pz9c"><step id = "bvin9nq"><para>In the Notification
area, right-click the iFolder application icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject
role="description"><phrase>iFolder Application Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject
role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png" width="11.00pt"
format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject>,
then click <guimenu>iFolders</guimenu> to open the iFolder browser.</para></step>
<step id = "bvinc1r"><para>Select the iFolder in conflict <inlinemediaobject><imageobject
role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder-error_16.png" width="11.00pt"
format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder-error_16.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject>,
then click <guimenu>Resolve</guimenu> to open the Resolve Conflicts
dialog box.</para></step>
<step id = "bx1anvu"><para>View the information for the file on
your local machine and the file on the server to determine which
version of the file you want to keep.</para></step>
<step id = "b47rm2p"><para>Beneath the version you want to keep,
click <guimenu>Save This Version</guimenu>.</para></step>
<step id = "bvincoe"><para>When you are done resolving the conflict,
click <guimenu>OK</guimenu>.</para></step></procedure>
<bridgehead id = "bx1arx6">Filename Conflicts</bridgehead>
<para>Filename conflicts occur when the names of the local file
version and the server file version differ by case. The content
might differ, or it might be the same. These type of conflicts can
be resolved by renaming the files, but be careful about where you
rename the file. </para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>If the content is the same, you can
rename one of the files in the Resolve Conflicts dialog box.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>If the content is different, make sure to make a
copy of the local file and give it a different name, then return
to the Resolve Conflicts dialog box and save the server version
of the file. This allows both versions of the file to exist in the
iFolder with different filenames. If you rename a file version within
the Resolve Conflicts dialog box, that version of the file overwrites
the other, and the content of the other file is destroyed. </para></listitem></itemizedlist>
<procedure id = "b25pz9d"><step id = "bx1b07o"><para>In the Notification
area, right-click the iFolder application icon <inlinemediaobject><textobject
role="description"><phrase>iFolder Application Icon </phrase></textobject><imageobject
role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png" width="11.00pt"
format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder22.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject>,
then click <guimenu>iFolders</guimenu> to open the iFolder browser.</para></step>
<step id = "bx1b07p"><para>Select the file in conflict <inlinemediaobject><imageobject
role="fo"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder-error_16.png" width="11.00pt"
format="PNG"/></imageobject>
<imageobject role="html"><imagedata fileref="graphics/ifolder-error_16.png"
width="11.00pt" format="png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject>,
then click <guimenu>Resolve</guimenu> to open the Resolve Conflicts
dialog box.</para></step>
<step id = "bx1atam"><para>Confirm that it is a file name conflict,
and determine whether the content is the same or different.</para></step>
<step id = "bx1au4u"><para>Do one of the following:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>If the content is the same, rename
one of the files, then click <guimenu>Save This Version</guimenu>,
then click <guimenu>OK</guimenu> to close the Resolve Conflicts
dialog box. You are done.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>If the content is different, continue with <xref
    linkend = "bx1au97" xrefstyle = "StepXRef"/>.</para></listitem></itemizedlist></step>
<step id = "bx1au97"><para>Close the Resolve Conflicts dialog box.</para></step>
<step id = "bx1b3p9"><para>Open a file manager and navigate to the
local copy of the file in conflict.</para></step>
<step id = "bx1b3xf"><para>Copy the file and save it with a unique
name in the iFolder. </para>
<para>iFolder synchronizes the file as a new file to the server
and member computers.</para></step>
<step id = "bx1b3k7"><para>Return to the <guimenu>Resolve Conflicts</guimenu> dialog
box, select the server version of the file, click <guimenu>Save
this Version</guimenu>, then click <guimenu>OK</guimenu>.</para>
<para>The server version of the file downloads to your local machine
and overwrites the local copy of the file by that name.</para></step></procedure></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "reverting"><title>Reverting an iFolder
to a Normal Folder</title>
<para>You can revert an iFolder to a normal folder for the local
computer. After it is reverted, the collaborative share relationship
remains for all the iFolder members, but the iFolder is no longer synchronized
to your current computer. It does not delete the iFolder and its
contents from member workstations or the server.</para>
<procedure id = "b25pz9e"><step id = "bq6lwn0"><para>In a file manager
or the iFolder browser, locate the iFolder that you want to revert
to a normal folder.</para></step>
<step id = "bq6lwn1"><para>Use one of the following methods:</para>
<itemizedlist><listitem><para>Right-click the iFolder, then click <menuchoice>
<guimenu>Revert to a Normal Folder</guimenu></menuchoice>.</para></listitem>
<listitem><para>Select the iFolder, then click <menuchoice><guimenu>Revert
to a Normal Folder</guimenu></menuchoice>.</para></listitem></itemizedlist>
<para>The iFolder icon changes to a normal folder icon. The data
remains untouched on all member computers.</para></step></procedure></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "movelocation"><title>Moving an iFolder</title>
<para>After you create an iFolder, the path to the iFolder is static.
You cannot move an iFolder from its original location to another
location on your local computer and have it remain an iFolder. Moving the
iFolder breaks the link between the synchronization database and
the folder you converted to an iFolder. </para>
<para>To move an iFolder on the computer where you created it:</para>
<procedure id = "b25pz9f"><step id = "bv5cbfn"><para>In a file manager
or the iFolder browser, select the iFolder you want to move.</para></step>
<step id = "b403aa8"><para>Revert the iFolder to a normal folder.</para></step>
<step id = "bv5cbj9"><para>In a file manager, move the folder to
another location on the computer.</para></step>
<step id = "bv5ccu2"><para>Convert the folder back to an iFolder
and upload the iFolder to the server.</para></step>
<step id = "bv5ccwu"><para>(Optional) Share the iFolder.</para></step>
<step id = "b41ty8l"><para>Allow the iFolder to synchronize files
with the iFolder server.</para></step></procedure>
<para>To move an iFolder on a participating computer:</para>
<procedure id = "b25pz9g"><step id = "bv5chii"><para>In iFolders,
revert the iFolder to stop participating in the iFolder on the current
computer.</para></step>
<step id = "bv5chij"><para>Select the available iFolder, then click <guimenu>Download
an iFolder</guimenu>.</para></step>
<step id = "bv5cgpu"><para>Specify a new local path where you want
to place the iFolder.</para></step>
<step id = "bv5cgpv"><para>Allow the iFolder to synchronize files
with the iFolder server.</para></step></procedure></sect1>
<sect1 role = "General" id = "deleting"><title>Deleting an iFolder</title>
<para>If you delete an iFolder from your collection, it deletes
the local copy of the iFolder and its contents. It also can affect
the share relationship for the iFolder, depending on the Access
right you hold for it. The following table outlines the effect on
the share relationship and the member iFolders based on the Access
right of the user who deletes the iFolder.</para>
<table id = "b403b0h" frame = "topbot" rowsep = "1" pgwide = "0">
<title>What to Expect When You Delete an iFolder</title>
<tgroup cols = "4">
<colspec colnum = "1" colname = "1" colwidth = "1.458in"/>
<colspec colnum = "2" colname = "2" colwidth = "1.458in"/>
<colspec colnum = "3" colname = "3" colwidth = "1.458in"/>
<colspec colnum = "4" colname = "4" colwidth = "1.458in"/>
<thead>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b403cby">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Access Right of the User Who Deletes
the iFolder</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Share Relationship</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>Server Copy of the iFolder</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Member Copies of the iFolder</para></entry>
</row>
</thead>
<tbody>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b403cbz">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Owner</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Ends the share relationship for the iFolder</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>Deletes the iFolder metadata and contents from
the server </para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Reverts the iFolder to a normal folder
for all users </para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b403cc0">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Full Control User</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Unsubscribes the user from the share</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>No effect</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Reverts the local copy of the iFolder
to a normal folder</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "1" id = "b403cc1">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Read&sol;Write User</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Unsubscribes the user from the share</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>No effect</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Reverts the local copy of the iFolder
to a normal folder</para></entry>
</row>
<row rowsep = "0" id = "b403cc2">
<entry colname = "1"><para>Read Only User</para></entry>
<entry colname = "2"><para>Unsubscribes the user from the share</para></entry>
<entry colname = "3"><para>No effect</para></entry>
<entry colname = "4"><para>Reverts the local copy of the iFolder
to a normal folder</para></entry>
</row>
</tbody>
</tgroup></table>
<para>Deleting an iFolder does not uninstall the iFolder client
from your workstation.</para>
<procedure id = "b25pz9h"><step id = "bq8ubrz"><para>In a file manager
or iFolder browser, locate the iFolder that you want to delete.</para></step>
<step id = "bq8u9b1"><para>Right-click the iFolder, then click <guimenu>Delete</guimenu>.</para></step></procedure></sect1></chapter>
</book>
